<handiworks>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Paraic Sheridan, Jean Paul Ballerini</authors>
        <title>Experiments in multilingual information retrieval using the SPIDER system</title>
        <year>1996</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 19th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in
            information retrieval
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Jan Hajiç, Barbora Hladka</authors>
        <title>Tagging inflective languages: prediction of morphological categories for a rich, structured tagset
        </title>
        <year>1998</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 17th international conference on Computational linguistics - Volume 1</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Zelal Gungordu, Kemal Oflazer</authors>
        <title>Parsing Turkish using the lexical functional grammar formalism</title>
        <year>1994</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 15th conference on Computational linguistics - Volume 1</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Gokhan Tur, Dilek Hakkani, Kemal Oflazer</authors>
        <title>A statistical information extraction system for Turkish</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <page>181-210</page>
        <journal>Nat. Lang. Eng.</journal>
        <number>2</number>
        <volume>9</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Deniz Yuret, Ferhan T, , 252, re</authors>
        <title>Learning morphological disambiguation rules for Turkish</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the main conference on Human Language Technology Conference of the North American
            Chapter of the Association of Computational Linguistics
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Peter Willett</authors>
        <title>Recent trends in hierarchic document clustering: a critical review</title>
        <year>1988</year>
        <page>577-597</page>
        <journal>Inf. Process. Manage.</journal>
        <number>5</number>
        <volume>24</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ellen M. Voorhees, Donna Harman</authors>
        <title>Overview of the sixth text REtrieval conference (TREC-6)</title>
        <year>2000</year>
        <page>3-35</page>
        <journal>Inf. Process. Manage.</journal>
        <number>1</number>
        <volume>36</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Toutanova, K., Manning, C. D.</authors>
        <title>Enriching the knowledge sources used in a maximum entropy part-of-speech tagger</title>
        <year>2000</year>
        <page>63-70 224</page>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 2000 Joint Sigdat Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing and
            Very Large Corpora
        </journal>
        <abstract>This paper presents results for a maximum-entropy-based part of speech tagger, which achieves superior
            performance principally by enriching the information sources used for tagging. In particular, we get
            improved results by incorporating these features: (i) more extensive treatment of capitalization for unknown
            words; (ii) features for the disambiguation of the tense forms of verbs; (iii) features for disambiguating
            particles from prepositions and adverbs. The best resulting accuracy for the tagger on the Penn Treebank is
            96.86% overall, and 86.91% on previously unseen words.
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Izumi Suzuki, Yoshiki Mikami, Ario Ohsato, Yoshihide Chubachi</authors>
        <title>A language and character set determination method based on N-gram statistics</title>
        <year>2002</year>
        <page>269-278</page>
        <journal>ACM Transactions on Asian Language Information Processing (TALIP)</journal>
        <number>3</number>
        <volume>1</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Strzalkowski, T.</authors>
        <title>Natural-Language Information-Retrieval</title>
        <year>1995</year>
        <page>397-417</page>
        <journal>Information Processing &amp; Management</journal>
        <number>3</number>
        <volume>31</volume>
        <abstract>In this paper we describe an information retrieval system in which advanced natural language
            processing techniques are used to enhance the effectiveness of term-based document retrieval. The backbone
            of our system is a traditional statistical engine that builds inverted index files from pre-processed
            documents, and then searches and ranks the documents in response to user queries. Natural language
            processing is used to (a) preprocess the documents in order to extract content carrying terms, (b) discover
            inter-term dependencies and build a conceptual hierarchy specific to the database domain, and (c) process
            the user's natural language requests into effective search queries. During the course of the Text REtrieval
            Conferences, TREC-1 and TREC-2, our system has evolved from a scaled-up prototype, originally tested on such
            collections as CACM-3204 and Cranfield, to its present form which can be effectively used to process
            hundreds of millions of words of unrestricted text.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Helmut Schmid</authors>
        <title>Part-of-speech tagging with neural networks</title>
        <year>1994</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 15th conference on Computational linguistics - Volume 1</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Savova, V., Peshkin, L.</authors>
        <title>Part-of-speech tagging with minimal lexicalization</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>163-172 402</page>
        <journal>Recent Advances in Natural Language Processing III</journal>
        <volume>260</volume>
        <abstract>We use a Dynamic Bayesian Network (DBN) to represent compactly a variety of sublexical and contextual
            features relevant to Part-of-Speech (POS) tagging. The outcome is a flexible tagger (LegoTag) with
            state-of-the-art performance (3.6% error on a benchmark corpus). We explore the effect of eliminating
            redundancy and radically reducing the size of feature vocabularies. We find that a small but linguistically
            motivated set of suffixes results in improved cross-corpora generalization. We also show that a minimal
            lexicon limited to function words is sufficient to ensure reasonable performance.
        </abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>C. J. Van Rijsbergen</authors>
        <title>Information Retrieval</title>
        <year>1979</year>
        <page>208</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Jeffrey C. Reynar, Adwait Ratnaparkhi</authors>
        <title>A maximum entropy approach to identifying sentence boundaries</title>
        <year>1997</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the fifth conference on Applied natural language processing</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Philip Resnik</authors>
        <title>Mining the Web for bilingual text</title>
        <year>1999</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 37th annual meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics on
            Computational Linguistics
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Palmer, D. D., Hearst, M. A.</authors>
        <title>Adaptive multilingual sentence boundary disambiguation</title>
        <year>1997</year>
        <page>241-267</page>
        <journal>Computational Linguistics</journal>
        <number>2</number>
        <volume>23</volume>
        <abstract>The sentence is a standard textual unit in natural language processing applications. In many languages
            the punctuation mark that indicates the end-of-sentence boundary is ambiguous; thus the tokenizers of most
            NLP systems must be equipped with special sentence boundary recognition rules for every new text collection.
            As an alternative, this article presents an efficient, trainable system for sentence boundary
            disambiguation. The system, called Satz, makes simple estimates of the parts of speech of the tokens
            immediately preceding and following each punctuation mark, and uses these estimates as input to a machine
            learning algorithm that then classifies the punctuation mark. Satz is very fast both in training and
            sentence analysis, and its combined robustness and accuracy surpass existing techniques. The system needs
            only a small lexicon and training corpus, and has been shown to transfer quickly and easily from English to
            ether languages, as demonstrated on French and German.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Oflazer, K., Tur, G.</authors>
        <title>Morphological disambiguation by voting constraints</title>
        <year>1997</year>
        <page>222-229 527</page>
        <journal>35th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics and the 8th Conference of the
            European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics, Proceedings of the Conference
        </journal>
        <abstract>We present a constraint-based morphological disambiguation system in which individual constraints vote
            on matching morphological parses, and disambiguation of all the tokens in a sentence is performed at the end
            by selecting parses that receive the highest votes. This constraint application paradigm makes the outcome
            of the disambiguation independent of the rule sequence, and hence relieves the rule developer from worrying
            about potentially conflicting rule sequencing. Our results for disambiguating Turkish indicate that using
            about 500 constraint rules and some additional simple statistics, we can attain a recall of 95-96% and a
            precision of 94-95% with about 1.01 parses per token. Our system is implemented in Prolog and we are
            currently investigating an efficient implementation based on finite state transducers.
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Andrei Mikheev</authors>
        <title>Tagging sentence boundaries</title>
        <year>2000</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 1st North American chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics
            conference
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Rafael Dueire Lins, Paulo Gon, , 231, alves</authors>
        <title>Automatic language identification of written texts</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 2004 ACM symposium on Applied computing</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Sanjay Jain, Arun Sharma</authors>
        <title>Probability is more powerful than team for language identification from positive data</title>
        <year>1993</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the sixth annual conference on Computational learning theory</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Beryl Ann Hoffman</authors>
        <title>The computational analysis of the syntax and interpretation of free word order in Turkish</title>
        <year>1995</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Hakkani-Tur, D. Z., Oflazer, K., Tur, G.</authors>
        <title>Statistical morphological disambiguation for agglutinative languages</title>
        <year>2002</year>
        <page>381-410</page>
        <journal>Computers and the Humanities</journal>
        <number>4</number>
        <volume>36</volume>
        <abstract>We present statistical models for morphological disambiguation in agglutinative languages, with a
            specific application to Turkish. Turkish presents an interesting problem for statistical models as the
            potential tag set size is very large because of the productive derivational morphology. We propose to handle
            this by breaking up the morhosyntactic tags into inflectional groups, each of which contains the
            inflectional features for each (intermediate) derived form. Our statistical models score the probability of
            each morhosyntactic tag by considering statistics over the individual inflectional groups and surface roots
            in trigram models. Among the four models that we have developed and tested, the simplest model ignoring the
            local morphotactics within words performs the best. Our best trigram model performs with 93.95% accuracy on
            our test data getting all the morhosyntactic and semantic features correct. If we are just interested in
            syntactically relevant features and ignore a very small set of semantic features, then the accuracy
            increases to 95.07%.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>P. Duygulu, Kobus Barnard, J. F. G. de Freitas, David A. Forsyth</authors>
        <title>Object Recognition as Machine Translation: Learning a Lexicon for a Fixed Image Vocabulary</title>
        <year>2002</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 7th European Conference on Computer Vision-Part IV</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Dincer, B. T., Karaoglan, B.</authors>
        <title>Sentence boundary detection in Turkish</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>255-262</page>
        <journal>Advances in Information Systems, Proceedings</journal>
        <volume>3261</volume>
        <abstract>In this paper, we describe a solution method for sentence boundary detection in Turkish. The method
            exploits simple heuristic knowledge of Turkish syllabication and its phonetic rules for disambiguation of
            dots. The test accuracy of the algorithm is measured as 96.02%. The main contribution of this study is
            considered as presenting a new lexicon free method for differentiating EOS (end of sentence) dots from the
            ones that are used for other purposes.
        </abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Dincer, B. T.</authors>
        <title>Statistical principal components analysis for retrieval experiments</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>560-574</page>
        <journal>Journal of the American Society for Information Science and Technology</journal>
        <number>4</number>
        <volume>58</volume>
        <abstract>In this article, the statistical principal components analysis (PCA) is proposed as a method for
            performance comparisons of different retrieval strategies. It is shown that the PCA method can reveal
            implicit performance relations among retrieval systems across information needs (i.e., queries, topics). For
            illustration, the TREC 12 robust track data have been reevaluated by the PCA method and have been shown to
            reveal easily the performance relations that are hard to see with traditional techniques. Therefore, PCA
            promises a uniform evaluation framework that can be used for large-scale evaluation of retrieval
            experiments. In addition to the mean average precision (MAP) measure, relative analytic distance (RAD) is
            proposed as a new performance summary measure based on the same notion introduced by PCA.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>A M Derouault, B Merialdo</authors>
        <title>Natural language modeling for phoneme-to-text transcription</title>
        <year>1986</year>
        <page>742-749</page>
        <journal>IEEE Trans. Pattern Anal. Mach. Intell.</journal>
        <number>6</number>
        <volume>8</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Evangelos Dermatas, George Kokkinakis</authors>
        <title>Automatic stochastic tagging of natural language texts</title>
        <year>1995</year>
        <page>137-163</page>
        <journal>Comput. Linguist.</journal>
        <number>2</number>
        <volume>21</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>James Cussens, Saso Dzeroski, Tomaz Erjavec</authors>
        <title>Morphosyntactic Tagging of Slovene Using Progol</title>
        <year>1999</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 9th International Workshop on Inductive Logic Programming</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>W. Bruce Croft, Howard R. Turtle, David D. Lewis</authors>
        <title>The use of phrases and structured queries in information retrieval</title>
        <year>1991</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 14th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in
            information retrieval
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Kenneth Ward Church</authors>
        <title>A stochastic parts program and noun phrase parser for unrestricted text</title>
        <year>1988</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the second conference on Applied natural language processing</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ozlem Cetinoglu, Kemal Oflazer</authors>
        <title>Morphology-syntax interface for Turkish LFG</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 21st International Conference on Computational Linguistics and the 44th annual
            meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Fazli Can, Esen A. Ozkarahan</authors>
        <title>Concepts and effectiveness of the cover-coefficient-based clustering methodology for text databases
        </title>
        <year>1990</year>
        <page>483-517</page>
        <journal>ACM Trans. Database Syst.</journal>
        <number>4</number>
        <volume>15</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Fazli Can, Seyit Kocberber, Ozgur Baglioglu, Suleyman Kardas, Huseyin Cagdas Ocalan, Erkan Uyar
        </authors>
        <title>Bilkent news portal: a personalizable system with new event detection and tracking capabilities</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 31st annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in
            information retrieval
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Bozsahin, C.</authors>
        <title>The combinatory morphemic lexicon</title>
        <year>2002</year>
        <page>145-186</page>
        <journal>Computational Linguistics</journal>
        <number>2</number>
        <volume>28</volume>
        <abstract>Grammars that expect words from the lexicon may be at odds with the transparent projection of
            syntactic and semantic scope relations of smaller units. We propose a morphosyntactic framework based on
            Combinatory Categorial Grammar that provides flexible constituency, flexible category consistency, and
            lexical projection of morphosyntactic properties and attachment to grammar in order to establish a morphemic
            grammar-lexicon. These mechanisms provide enough expressive power in the lexicon to formulate semantically
            transparent specifications without the necessity to confine structure forming to words and phrases. For
            instance, bound morphemes as lexical items can have phrasal scope or word scope, independent of their
            attachment characteristics but consistent with their semantics. The controls can be attuned in the lexicon
            to language-particular properties. The result is a transparent interface of inflectional morphology, syntax,
            and semantics. We present a computational system and show the application of the framework to English and
            Turkish.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>G. Edward Barton</authors>
        <title>Computational complexity in two-level morphology</title>
        <year>1986</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 24th annual meeting on Association for Computational Linguistics</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>James K. Baker</authors>
        <title>Stochastic modeling for automatic speech understanding</title>
        <year>1990</year>
        <page>297-307</page>
        <journal>Readings in speech recognition</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>James Allan, Jay Aslam, Nicholas Belkin, Chris Buckley, Jamie Callan, Bruce Croft, Sue Dumais, Norbert
            Fuhr, Donna Harman, David J. Harper, Djoerd Hiemstra, Thomas Hofmann, Eduard Hovy, Wessel Kraaij, John
            Lafferty, Victor Lavrenko, David Lewis, Liz Liddy, R. Manmatha, Andrew McCallum, Jay Ponte, John Prager,
            Dragomir Radev, Philip Resnik, Stephen Robertson, Roni Rosenfeld, Salim Roukos, Mark Sanderson, Rich
            Schwartz, Amit Singhal, Alan Smeaton, Howard Turtle, Ellen Voorhees, Ralph Weischedel, Jinxi Xu, ChengXiang
            Zhai
        </authors>
        <title>Challenges in information retrieval and language modeling: report of a workshop held at the center for
            intelligent information retrieval, University of Massachusetts Amherst, September 2002
        </title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <page>31-47</page>
        <journal>SIGIR Forum</journal>
        <number>1</number>
        <volume>37</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>John Aberdeen, John Burger, David Day, Lynette Hirschman, Patricia Robinson, Marc Vilain</authors>
        <title>MITRE: description of the Alembic system used for MUC-6</title>
        <year>1995</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 6th conference on Message understanding</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ted, Dunning</authors>
        <title>Accurate M ethods for the S tatistics of S urprise and C oincidence</title>
        <year>1993</year>
        <page>61-74</page>
        <journal>Computational Linguistics</journal>
        <number>1</number>
        <volume>19</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Jinxi, Xu, W. Bruce Croft</authors>
        <title>Improving the E ffectiveness of I nformation R etrieval with L ocal C ontext A nalysis</title>
        <year>2000</year>
        <page>79-112</page>
        <journal>ACM Transactions on Information Systems (TOIS)</journal>
        <number>1</number>
        <volume>18</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Badrul, Sarwar, George, Karypis, Joseph, Konstan, John, Reidl</authors>
        <title>Item- B ased C ollaborative F iltering R ecommendation A lgorithms</title>
        <year>2001</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 10th I nternational C onference on World Wide Web</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Hang, Cui, Ji-Rong, Wen, Jian-Yun, Nie</authors>
        <title>Query Expansion by Mining User Logs</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <page>829-839</page>
        <journal>IEEE Trans. on Knowl. and Data Eng.</journal>
        <number>4</number>
        <volume>15</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Hang, Cui, Ji-Rong, Wen, Jian-Yun, Nie, Wei-Ying, Ma</authors>
        <title>Probabilistic Q uery E xpansion U sing Q uery L ogs</title>
        <year>2002</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 11th I nternational C onference on World Wide Web</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Thomas Reutterer, Andreas Mild, Martin Natter, Alfred Taudes</authors>
        <title>A D ynamic S egmentation A pproach for T argeting and C ustomizing D irect M arketing C ampaigns</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <page>43-57</page>
        <journal>JOURNAL OF INTERACTIVE MARKETING</journal>
        <number>3-4</number>
        <volume>20</volume>
        <abstract>An important aspect of customer relationship management is the targeting of customer segments with
            tailored promotional activities. While most contributions focus on the selection of promising customers for
            targeting, only few authors address the question of which specific differential offers to be directed to the
            selected target groups. We focus on both of these issues and propose a flexible two-stage approach for
            dynamically deriving behaviorally persistent segments and subsequent target marketing selection using retail
            purchase histories from loyalty program members. The underlying concept of behavioral persistence entails an
            in-depth analysis of complementary cross-category purchase interdependencies at a segment level. The
            effectiveness and efficiency of the proposed procedure is demonstrated in a controlled field experiment
            involving targeting of several thousands of customers enrolled in the loyalty program of a ?do-it-yourself?
            retailer. Our empirical findings provide evidence of significant positive impacts on both profitability and
            sales for segment-specific tailored direct marketing campaigns.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Michelle Anderson, Marcel Ball, Harold Boley, Stephen Greene, Nancy Howse, Daniel Lemire, Sean
            McGrath
        </authors>
        <title>RACOFI: A Rule-Applying Collaborative Filtering System</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <journal>In Proceedings of IEEE/WIC COLA'03</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Xiaodong, Shi, Christopher, C. Yang</authors>
        <title>Mining related queries from Web search engine query logs using an improved association rule mining
            model
        </title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>1871-1883</page>
        <journal>J. Am. Soc. Inf. Sci. Technol.</journal>
        <number>12</number>
        <volume>58</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Vechtomova, Olga, Wang, Ying</authors>
        <title>A study of the effect of term proximity on query expansion</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <page>324-333</page>
        <journal>Journal of Information Science</journal>
        <number>4</number>
        <volume>32</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Buckley, Chris, Salton, Gerard, Allan, James, Singhal, Amit</authors>
        <title>Automatic Query Expansion Using SMART: TREC 3</title>
        <year>1994</year>
        <journal>TREC</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Scott Deerwester, Susan T. Dumais, George W. Furnas, Thomas K. Landauer, Richard Harshman</authors>
        <title>Indexing by Latent Semantic Analysis</title>
        <year>1990</year>
        <page>391-407</page>
        <journal>Journal of the American Society for Information Science</journal>
        <volume>41</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ji-Rong, Wen, Jian-Yun, Nie, Hong-Jiang, Zhang</authors>
        <title>Clustering U ser Q ueries of a S earch E ngine</title>
        <year>2001</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 10th I nternational C onference on World Wide Web</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Jonathan, L. Herlocker, Joseph, A. Konstan, Al, Borchers, John, Riedl</authors>
        <title>An A lgorithmic F ramework for P erforming C ollaborative F iltering</title>
        <year>1999</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 22nd A nnual I nternational ACM SIGIR C onference on Research and D evelopment in I
            nformation R etrieval
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Yonggang, Qiu, Hans-Peter, Frei</authors>
        <title>Concept B ased Q uery E xpansion</title>
        <year>1993</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 16th A nnual I nternational ACM SIGIR C onference on Research and D evelopment in I
            nformation R etrieval
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Yufeng, Jing, W. B. Croft</authors>
        <title>An Association Thesaurus for Information Retrieval</title>
        <year>1994</year>
        <page>146-160</page>
        <journal>In Proceeding of RIAO</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>John S. Breese, David Heckerman, Carl Kadie, Morgan Kaufmann Publishers</authors>
        <title>Empirical Analysis of Predictive Algorithms for Collaborative Filtering</title>
        <year>1998</year>
        <page>18</page>
        <number>MSR-TR-98-12</number>
        <abstract>Collaborative filtering or recommender systems use a database about user preferences to predict
            additional topics or products a new user might like. In this paper we describe several algorithms designed
            for this task, including techniques based on correlation coefficients, vector-based similarity calculations,
            and statistical Bayesian methods. We compare the predictive accuracy of the various methods in a set of
            representative problem domains. We use two basic classes of evaluation metrics. The first characterizes
            accuracy over a set of individual predictions in terms of average absolute deviation. The second estimates
            the utility of a ranked list of suggested items. This metric uses an estimate of the probability that a user
            will see a recommendation in an ordered list. Experiments were run for datasets associated with 3
            application areas, 4 experimental protocols, and the 2 evaluation metrics for the various algorithms.
            Results indicate that for a wide range of conditions, Bayesian networks with decision trees at each node and
            correlation methods outperform Bayesian-clustering and vector-similarity methods. Between correlation and
            Bayesian networks, the preferred method depends on the nature of the dataset, nature of the application
            (ranked versus one-by-one presentation), and the availability of votes with which to make predictions. Other
            considerations include the size of database, speed of predictions, and learning time.
        </abstract>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Olena Medelyan, Paul Egr´e and Laura Alonso i Alemany</authors>
        <title>Why Not Use Query Logs As Corpora?</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the Ninth ESSLLI Student Session</journal>
        <abstract>Generally, every Web search engine logs the user sessions. These records, called query logs, contain
            valuable information about the behaviour of Internet users and their language. There are only a few
            experiments on mining query logs, but they confirm that query logs are very useful for designing natural
            language applications in Web retrieval. This paper shows how lexical and semantic information can be
            extracted from query logs using statistical methods. I first summarize approaches in query log processing
            and mining for different purposes. After a short description of the used query logs, I present new domain-
            and language-independent methods for generating a compound dictionary and extracting semantically similar
            terms. The evaluation will shed light on the quality of proposed methods and show that the results are good
            enough to be directly integrated in query processing and improve information retrieval on the Web.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Punam Bedi, Suruchi Chawla</authors>
        <title>Improving Information Retrieval Precision Using Query Log Mining and Information Scent</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>584-588</page>
        <journal>Information Technology Journal</journal>
        <number>4</number>
        <volume>6</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Kamal Ali, Wijnand van Stam</authors>
        <title>TiVo: Making Show Recommendations using a Distributed Collaborative Filtering Architecture</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the tenth ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Suruchi Chawla, Dr Punam Bedi</authors>
        <title>Improving Information Retrieval Precision by Finding Related Queries with Similar Information Need Using
            Information Scent
        </title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <page>486-491</page>
        <journal>First International Conference on Emerging Trends in Engineering and Technology ICETET '08</journal>
        <abstract>Web is a valuable source of information and it is expanding at an enormous speed. Search engines
            provide the interface to access to this vast pool of information. Users express their information need
            through the input query to retrieve the relevant information which does not prove to be effective as input
            query entered by the user is too short to get the information need of the user. To retrieve the information
            according to a particular information need from a big pool of information available on the web is a big
            challenge. This paper proposes a method to find the related queries which approximate the information need
            of the input query issued to the search engine. This is accomplished using Information scent and content of
            clicked pages in query sessions mining. Information scent is derived from the information foraging theory in
            which user behavior in the information environment is guided by information scent. Information need of the
            query sessions is modeled using information scent and content of clicked URLs and query sessions with
            similar information need are clustered. The clusters which closely approximate the information need of input
            query are used to suggest queries with similar information need for a given input query. The suggested
            queries are ranked in order of their degree of relevance with respect to information need of the input
            query. Retrieval precision of search engine is improved as suggested queries help to retrieve document
            relevant to the need of user efficiently and quickly. Experimental study has been conducted on the dataset
            collected from Google search engine Web history to confirm the improvement of precision of information
            retrieval.
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Pavel Berkhin</authors>
        <title>Survey Of Clustering Data Mining Techniques</title>
        <year>2002</year>
        <abstract>Clustering is a division of data into groups of similar objects. Representing the data by fewer
            clusters neccessarily loses certain fine details, but achieves simplification. It models data by its
            clusters. Data modeling puts clustering in a historial perspective rooted in mathematics, statistics and
            numerical analysis. From a machine learning perspective clusters correspond to hidden patterns, the search
            for clusters in unsupervised learning and the resulting system represents a data concept....
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ricardo Baeza-Yates, Carlos Hurtado, Marcelo Mendoza</authors>
        <title>Query Recommendation Using Query Logs in Search Engines</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>588--596</page>
        <journal>Current Trends in Database Technology - EDBT 2004 Workshops</journal>
        <volume>3268/2004</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>David M W Powers</authors>
        <title>Evaluation: From Precision, Recall and F-Factor to ROC, Informedness, Markedness and Correlation</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <number>SIE-07-001</number>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>JI-RONG WEN, JIAN-YUN NIE, HONG-JIANG ZHANG</authors>
        <title>Query Clustering using User Logs</title>
        <year>2002</year>
        <page>59-81</page>
        <journal>ACM Transactions on Information System</journal>
        <number>1</number>
        <volume>20</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Xuanhui Wang, Bin Tan, Azadeh Shakery, ChengXiang Zhai</authors>
        <title>Search Logs as Information Footprints: Supporting Guided Navigation for Exploratory Search</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <journal>Computer Science Research and Tech Reports</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ryen W. White, Charles L. A. Clarke, Silviu Cucerzan</authors>
        <title>Comparing query logs and pseudo-relevance feedbackfor web-search query refinement</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 30th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in
            information retrieval
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Mehmet Emin Kucuk, Baha Olgun, Hayri Sever</authors>
        <title>Application of metadata concepts to discovery of Internet resources</title>
        <year>2000</year>
        <page>304- 3 13</page>
        <journal>Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNCS), Springer Verlag</journal>
        <volume>1909</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Aysin Solak, Kemal Oflazer</authors>
        <title>Design and Implementation of a Spelling Checker for Turkish</title>
        <year>1993</year>
        <page>113-130</page>
        <journal>Literary and Linguistic Computing, 8(3), 1993</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>A C iltik, Tunga Gungor</authors>
        <title>Developing Methods and Heuristics with Low Time Complexities for Filtering Spam Messages</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <journal>12th International Conference on Applications of Natural Language to Information Systems (NLDB 2007),
            June 2007, Paris
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Arslan, Ahmet, Yilmazel, Ozgur</authors>
        <title>A comparison of Relational Databases and information retrieval libraries on Turkish text retrieval
        </title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <page>1-8</page>
        <journal>Natural Language Processing and Knowledge Engineering, 2008. NLP-KE '08. International Conference on
        </journal>
        <abstract>The present work covers a comparison of the text retrieval performances of relational databases and IR
            Systems over a TREC-like test collection for Turkish. The effects of language specific preprocessing and
            different query lengths for different information retrieval systems are investigated. Showed that language
            specific preprocessing improves retrieval performance for all systems and also Relational Databases are
            slower with longer queries.
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Andrés Corrada-Emmanuel, W. Bruce Croft</authors>
        <title>Answer models for question answering passage retrieval</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 27th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in
            information retrieval
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Jiwoon Jeon, W. Bruce Croft, Joon Ho Lee</authors>
        <title>Finding similar questions in large question and answer archives</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 14th ACM international conference on Information and knowledge management</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Jiwoon Jeon, W. Bruce Croft, Joon Ho Lee, Soyeon Park</authors>
        <title>A framework to predict the quality of answers with non-textual features</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 29th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in
            information retrieval
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Xiaobing Xue, Jiwoon Jeon, W. Bruce Croft</authors>
        <title>Retrieval models for question and answer archives</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 31st annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in
            information retrieval
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Christian Middleton, Ricardo Baeza-Yates</authors>
        <title>A Comparision of Open Source Search Engines</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Jiwoon Jeon</authors>
        <title>Searching question and answer archives</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>147</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Gao Cong, Long Wang, Chin-Yew Lin, Young-In Song, Yueheng Sun</authors>
        <title>Finding question-answer pairs from online forums</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 31st annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in
            information retrieval
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Dan Isaac Slobin, Karl Zimmer</authors>
        <title>Studies In Turk i sh Linguistics</title>
        <year>1986</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>CIP-GEGEVENS KONINKLUKE BIBUOTKEK DEN HAAG</authors>
        <title>Studies on modern Turkish</title>
        <year>1987</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the third conference on Turkish linguistics</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Benjamin E. Teitler, Michael D. Lieberman, Daniele Panozzo, Jagan Sankaranarayanan, Hanan Samet, Jon
            Sperling
        </authors>
        <title>NewsStand: a new view on news</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 16th ACM SIGSPATIAL international conference on Advances in geographic information
            systems
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Huifeng Li, Rohini K. Srihari, Cheng Niu, Wei Li</authors>
        <title>InfoXtract location normalization: a hybrid approach to geographic references in information extraction
        </title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the HLT-NAACL 2003 workshop on Analysis of geographic references</journal>
        <volume>1</volume>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Einat Amitay, Nadav Har&amp;apos,El, Ron Sivan, Aya Soffer</authors>
        <title>Web-a-where: geotagging web content</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 27th annual international ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in
            information retrieval
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Wang, Yang, Ji, Qiang</authors>
        <title>A Dynamic Conditional Random Field Model for Object Segmentation in Image Sequences</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <journal>In IEEE Computer Society Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR 2005)</journal>
        <abstract>This paper presents a dynamic conditional random field (DCRF) model to integrate contextual
            constraints for object segmentation in image sequences. Spatial and temporal dependencies within the
            segmentation process are unified by a dynamic probabilistic framework based on the conditional random field
            (CRF). An efficient approximate filtering algorithm is derived for the DCRF model to recursively estimate
            the segmentation field from the history of video frames. The segmentation method employs both intensity and
            motion cues, and it combines dynamic information and spatial interaction of the observed data. Experimental
            results show that the proposed approach effectively fuses contextual constraints in video sequences and
            improves the accuracy of object segmentation.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Wallach, Hanna M.</authors>
        <title>Conditional random Fields: An Introduction</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Wallach, Hanna</authors>
        <title>Efficient Training of Conditional Random Fields</title>
        <year>2002</year>
        <journal>School of Cognitive Science Division of Informatics</journal>
        <volume>Master of Science</volume>
        <abstract>This thesis explores a number of parameter estimation techniques for conditional random fields, a
            recently introduced probabilistic model for labelling and segmenting sequential data. Theoretical and
            practical disadvantages of the training techniques reported in current literature on CRFs are discussed. We
            hypothesise that general numerical optimisation techniques result in improved performance over iterative
            scaling algorithms for training CRFs. Experiments run on a subset of a well-known text chunking data set
            confirm that this is indeed the case. This is a highly promising result, indicating that such parameter
            estimation techniques make CRFs a practical and efficient choice for labelling sequential data, as well as a
            theoretically sound and principled probabilistic framework.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Torralba, Antonio, Murphy, Kevin P., Freeman, William T.</authors>
        <title>Contextual Models for Object Detection using Boosted Random Fields</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <page>1401-1408</page>
        <journal>In Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 17 (NIPS 2004)</journal>
        <abstract>We seek to both detect and segment objects in images. To exploit both local image data as well as
            contextual information, we introduce Boosted Random Fields (BRFs), which uses Boosting to learn the graph
            structure and local evidence of a conditional random field (CRF). The graph structure is learned by
            assembling graph fragments in an additive model. The connections between individual pixels are not very
            informative, but by using dense graphs, we can pool information from large regions of the image; dense
            models also support efficient inference. We show how contextual information from other objects can improve
            detection performance, both in terms of accuracy and speed, by using a computational cascade. We apply our
            system to detect stuff and things in office and street scenes.
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Taskar, Ben, Guestrin, Carlos, Koller, Daphne</authors>
        <title>Max Margin Markov Networks</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>In Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 16 (NIPS 2003), 2004</journal>
        <abstract>In typical classification tasks, we seek a function which assigns a label to a single object.
            Kernel-based approaches, such as support vector machines (SVMs), which maximize the margin of confidence of
            the classifier, are the method of choice for many such tasks. Their popularity stems both from the ability
            to use high-dimensional feature spaces, and from their strong theoretical guarantees. However, many
            real-world tasks involve sequential, spatial, or structured data, where multiple labels must be assigned.
            Existing kernel-based methods ignore structure in the problem, assigning labels independently to each
            object, losing much useful information. Conversely, probabilistic graphical models, such as Markov networks,
            can represent correlations between labels, by exploiting problem structure, but cannot handle
            high-dimensional feature spaces, and lack strong theoretical generalization guarantees. In this paper, we
            present a new framework that combines the advantages of both approaches: Maximum margin Markov (M3) networks
            incorporate both kernels, which efficiently deal with high-dimensional features, and the ability to capture
            correlations in structured data. We present an efficient algorithm for learning M3 networks based on a
            compact quadratic program formulation. We provide a new theoretical bound for generalization in structured
            domains. Experiments on the task of handwritten character recognition and collective hypertext
            classification demonstrate very significant gains over previous approaches.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Sutton, Charles, Rohanimanesh, Khashayar, McCallum, Andrew</authors>
        <title>Dynamic Conditional Random Fields: Factorized Probabilistic Models for Labeling and Segmenting Sequence
            Data
        </title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>In Proceedings of the Twenty-First International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML 2004)</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Sutton, Charles, McCallum, Andrew, Rohanimanesh, Khashayar</authors>
        <title>Dynamic Conditional Random Fields: Factorized Probabilistic Models for Labeling and Segmenting Sequence
            Data
        </title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>693-723</page>
        <journal>The Journal of Machine Learning Research</journal>
        <volume>8</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Sutton, Charles, McCallum, Andrew, Getoor, Lise, Taskar, Ben</authors>
        <title>An Introduction to Conditional Random Fields for Relational Learning</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <journal>Introduction to Statistical Relational Learning</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Smimchisescu, Cristian, Kanaujia, Atul, Li, Zhiguo, Metaxus, Dimitris</authors>
        <title>Conditional Models for Contextual Human Motion Recognition</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <journal>In Proceedings of the International Conference on Computer Vision, (ICCV 2005)</journal>
        <abstract>We present algorithms for recognizing human motion in monocular video sequences, based on
            discriminative Conditional Random Field (CRF) and Maximum Entropy Markov Models (MEMM). Existing approaches
            to this problem typically use generative (joint) structures like the Hidden Markov Model (HMM). Therefore
            they have to make simplifying, often unrealistic assumptions on the conditional independence of observations
            given the motion class labels and cannot accommodate overlapping features or long term contextual
            dependencies in the observation sequence. In contrast, conditional models like the CRFs seamlessly represent
            contextual dependencies, support efficient, exact inference using dynamic programming, and their parameters
            can be trained using convex optimization. We introduce conditional graphical models as complementary tools
            for human motion recognition and present an extensive set of experiments that show how these typically
            outperform HMMs in classifying not only diverse human activities like walking, jumping, running, picking or
            dancing, but also for discriminating among subtle motion styles like normal walk and wander walk.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Sha, Fei, Pereira, Fernando</authors>
        <title>Shallow Parsing With Conditional Random Fields</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <journal>In Proceedings of the 2003 Human Language Technology Conference and North American Chapter of the
            Association for Computational Linguistics (HLT/NAACL-03)
        </journal>
        <abstract>Conditional random fields for sequence labeling offer advantages over both generative models like HMMs
            and classifers applied at each sequence position. Among sequence labeling tasks in language processing,
            shallow parsing has received much attention, with the development of standard evaluation datasets and
            extensive comparison among methods. We show here how to train a conditional random field to achieve
            performance as good as any reported base noun-phrase chunking method on the CoNLL task, and better than any
            reported single model. Improved training methods based on modern optimization algorithms were critical in
            achieving these results. We present extensive comparisons between models and training methods that confirm
            and strengthen previous results on shallow parsing and training methods for maximum-entropy models.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Settles, Burr</authors>
        <title>Biomedical Named Entity Recognition Using Conditional Random Fields and Rich Feature Set</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>104-107</page>
        <journal>In Proceedings of the International Joint Workshop on Natural Language Processing in Biomedicine and
            Its Applications (NLPBA)
        </journal>
        <abstract>As the wealth of biomedical knowledge in the form of literature increases, there is a rising need for
            effective natural language processing tools to assist in organizing, curating, and retrieving this
            information. To that end, named entity recognition (the task of identifying words and phrases in free text
            that belong to certain classes of interest) is an important first step for many of these larger information
            management goals. In recent years, much attention has been focused on the problem of recognizing gene and
            protein mentions in biomedical abstracts. This paper presents a framework for simultaneously recognizing
            occurrences of PROTEIN, DNA, RNA, CELL-LINE, and CELL-TYPE entity classes using Conditional Random Fields
            with a variety of traditional and novel features. I show that this approach can achieve an overall F measure
            around 70, which seems to be the current state of the art.
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Sarawagi, Sunita, Cohen, William W.</authors>
        <title>Semi-Markov Conditional Random Fields for Information Extraction</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <journal>In Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 17 (NIPS 2004)</journal>
        <abstract>We describe semi-Markov conditional random fields (semi-CRFs), a conditionally trained version of
            semi-Markov chains. Intuitively, a semi-CRF on an input sequence x outputs a segmentation of x, in which
            labels are assigned to segments (i.e., subsequences) of x rather than to individual elements xi of x.
            Importantly, features for semi-CRFs can measure properties of segments, and transitions within a segment can
            be non-Markovian. In spite of this additional power, exact learning and inference algorithms for semi-CRFs
            are polynomial-time?often only a small constant factor slower than conventional CRFs. In experiments on five
            named entity recognition problems, semi-CRFs generally outperform conventional CRFs.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Roark, Brian, Saraclar, Murat, Collins, Michael, Johnson, Mark</authors>
        <title>Discriminative Language Modeling with Conditional Random Fields and the Perceptron Algorithm</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>In Proceedings of the 42nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL 2004)
        </journal>
        <abstract>This paper describes discriminative language modeling for a large vocabulary speech recognition task.
            We contrast two parameter estimation methods: the perceptron algorithm, and a method based on conditional
            random fields (CRFs). The models are encoded as deterministic weighted finite state automata, and are
            applied by intersecting the automata with word-lattices that are the output from a baseline recognizer. The
            perceptron algorithm has the benefit of automatically selecting a relatively small feature set in just a
            couple of passes over the training data. However, using the feature set output from the perceptron algorithm
            (initialized with their weights), CRF training provides an additional 0.5% reduction in word error rate, for
            a total 1.8% absolute reduction from the baseline of 39.2%.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Quattoni, Ariadna, Collins, Michael, Darrel, Trevor, Saul, Lawrence, Weiss, Yair, Bottou, Leon
        </authors>
        <title>Conditional Random Fields for Object Recognition</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <page>1097-1104</page>
        <journal>In Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 17 (NIPS 2004)</journal>
        <abstract>We present a discriminative part-based approach for the recognition of object classes from unsegmented
            cluttered scenes. Objects are modeled as flexible constellations of parts conditioned on local observations
            found by an interest operator. For each object class the probability of a given assignment of parts to local
            features is modeled by a Conditional Random Field (CRF). We propose an extension of the CRF framework that
            incorporates hidden variables and combines class conditional CRFs into a unified framework for part-based
            object recognition. The parameters of the CRF are estimated in a maximum likelihood framework and
            recognition proceeds by finding the most likely class under our model. The main advantage of the proposed
            CRF framework is that it allows us to relax the assumption of conditional independence of the observed data
            (i.e. local features) often used in generative approaches, an assumption that might be too restrictive for a
            considerable number of object classes. We illustrate the potential of the model in the task of recognizing
            cars from rear and side views.
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Qi, Yuan, Szummer, Martin, Minka, Thomas P.</authors>
        <title>Bayesian Conditional Random Fields</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <journal>To appear in Proceedings of the Tenth International Workshop on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics
            (AISTATS 2005)
        </journal>
        <abstract>We propose Bayesian Conditional Random Fields (BCRFs) for classifying interdependent and structured
            data, such as sequences, images or webs. BCRFs are a Bayesian approach to training and inference with
            conditional random fields, which were previously trained by maximizing likelihood (ML) (Lafferty et al.,
            2001). Our framework eliminates the problem of overfitting, and offers the full advantages of a Bayesian
            treatment. Unlike the ML approach, we estimate the posterior distribution of the model parameters during
            training, and average over this posterior during inference. We apply an extension of EP method, the power EP
            method, to incorporate the partition function. For algorithmic stability and accuracy, we flatten the
            approximation structures to avoid two-level approximations. We demonstrate the superior prediction accuracy
            of BCRFs over conditional random fields trained with ML or MAP on synthetic and real datasets.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Pinto, David, McCallum, Andrew, Wei, Xing, Croft, W. Bruce</authors>
        <title>Table Extraction Using Conditional Random Fields</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <journal>In Proceedings of the 26th Annual International ACM SIGIR Conference on Research and Development in
            Informaion Retrieval (SIGIR 2003)
        </journal>
        <abstract>The ability to find tables and extract information from them is a necessary component of data mining,
            question answering, and other information retrieval tasks. Documents often contain tables in order to
            communicate densely packed, multi-dimensional information. Tables do this by employing layout patterns to e
            ciently indicate fields and records in two-dimensional form. Their rich combination of formatting and
            content present di culties for traditional language modeling techniques, however. This paper presents the
            use of conditional random fields (CRFs) for table extraction, and compares them with hidden Markov models
            (HMMs). Unlike HMMs, CRFs support the use of many rich and overlapping layout and language features, and as
            a result, they perform significantly better. We show experimental results on plain-text government
            statistical reports in which tables are located with 92% F1, and their constituent lines are classified into
            12 table-related categories with 94% accuracy. We also discuss future work on undirected graphical models
            for segmenting columns, finding cells, and classifying them as data cells or label cells.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Peng, Fuchun, McCallum, Andrew</authors>
        <title>Accurate Information Extraction from Research Papers using Conditional Random Fields</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>In Proceedings of Human Language Technology Conference and North American Chapter of the Association
            for Computational Linguistics (HLT/NAACL-04)
        </journal>
        <abstract>With the increasing use of research paper search engines, such as CiteSeer, for both literature search
            and hiring decisions, the accuracy of such systems is of paramount importance. This paper employs
            Conditional Random Fields (CRFs) for the task of extracting various common fields from the headers and
            citation of research papers. The basic theory of CRFs is becoming well-understood, but best-practices for
            applying them to real-world data requires additional exploration. This paper makes an empirical exploration
            of several factors, including variations on Gaussian, exponential and hyperbolic priors for improved
            regularization, and several classes of features and Markov order. On a standard benchmark data set, we
            achieve new state-of-the-art performance, reducing error in average F1 by 36%, and word error rate by 78% in
            comparison with the previous best SVM results. Accuracy compares even more favorably against HMMs.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Murphy, Kevin, Torralba, Antonio, Freeman, William, Thrun, Sebastian, Saul, Lawrence, Bernhard
        </authors>
        <title>Using the Forest to See the Trees: A Graphical Model For Recognizing Scenes and Objects</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 16 (NIPS 2003)</journal>
        <abstract>Standard approaches to object detection focus on local patches of the image, and try to classify them
            as background or not. We propose to use the scene context (image as a whole) as an extra source of (global)
            information, to help resolve local ambiguities. We present a conditional random field for jointly solving
            the tasks of object detection and scene classification.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>McDonald, Ryan, Pereira, Fernando</authors>
        <title>Identifying Gene and Protein Mentions in Text Using Conditional Random Fields</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>McCallum, Andrew, Rohanimanesh, Khashayar, Sutton, Charles</authors>
        <title>Dynamic Conditional Random Fields for Jointly Labeling Multiple Sequences</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>Workshop on Syntax, Semantics, Statistics; 16th Annual Conference on Neural Information Processing
            Systems (NIPS 2003)
        </journal>
        <abstract>Conditional random fields (CRFs) for sequence modeling have several advantages over joint models such
            as HMMs, including the ability to relax strong independence assumptions made in those models, and the
            ability to incorporate arbitrary overlapping features. Previous work has focused on linear-chain CRFs, which
            correspond to finite-state machines, and have efficient exact inference algorithms. Often, however, we wish
            to label sequence data in multiple interacting ways?for example, performing part-of-speech tagging and noun
            phrase segmentation simultaneously, increasing joint accuracy by sharing information between them. We
            present dynamic conditional random fields (DCRFs), which are CRFs in which each time slice has a set of
            state variables and edges?a distributed state representation as in dynamic Bayesian networks?and parameters
            are tied across slices. (They could also be called conditionally-trained Dynamic Markov Networks.) Since
            exact inference can be intractable in these models, we perform approximate inference using the tree-based
            reparameterization framework (TRP). We also present empirical results comparing DCRFs with linear-chain CRFs
            on natural-language data.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>McCallum, Andrew, Li, Wei</authors>
        <title>Early Results for Named Entity Recognition with Conditional Random Fields, Feature Induction and
            Web-Enhanced Lexicons
        </title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <journal>In Proceedings of the Seventh Conference on Natural Language Learning (CoNLL)</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>McCallum, Andrew</authors>
        <title>Efficiently Inducing Features of Conditional Random Fields</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <journal>In Proceedings of the Nineteenth Conference in Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence (UAI-03)
        </journal>
        <abstract>Conditional Random Fields (CRFs) are undirected graphical models, a special case of which correspond
            to conditionally-trained finite state machines. A key advantage of CRFs is their great flexibility to
            include a wide variety of arbitrary, non-independent features of the input. Faced with this freedom,
            however, an important question remains: what features should be used? This paper presents an efficient
            feature induction method for CRFs. The method is founded on the principle of iteratively constructing
            feature conjunctions that would significantly increase conditional log-likelihood if added to the model.
            Automated feature induction enables not only improved accuracy and dramatic reduction in parameter count,
            but also the use of larger cliques, and more freedom to liberally hypothesize atomic input variables that
            may be relevant to a task. The method applies to linear-chain CRFs, as well as to more arbitrary CRF
            structures, such as Relational Markov Networks, where it corresponds to learning clique templates, and can
            also be understood as supervised structure learning. Experimental results on named entity extraction and
            noun phrase segmentation tasks are presented.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Li, Wei, McCallum, Andrew</authors>
        <title>Rapid Development of Hindi Named Entity Recognition using Conditional Random Fields and Feature
            Induction
        </title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <page>290-294</page>
        <journal>In ACM Transactions on Asian Language Information Processing (TALIP)</journal>
        <number>3</number>
        <volume>2</volume>
        <abstract>This paper describes our application of conditional random fields with feature induction to a Hindi
            named entity recognition task. With only five days development time and little knowledge of this language,
            we automatically discover relevant features by providing a large array of lexical tests and using feature
            induction to automatically construct the features that most increase conditional likelihood. In an effort to
            reduce overfitting, we use a combination of a Gaussian prior and early stopping based on the results of
            10-fold cross validation.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Lafferty, John D., McCallum, Andrew, Pereira, Fernando C. N.</authors>
        <title>Conditional Random Fields: Probabilistic Models for Segmenting and Labeling Sequence Data</title>
        <year>2001</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the Eighteenth International Conference on Machine Learning</journal>
        <abstract>We present conditional random fields, a framework for building probabilistic models to segment and
            label sequence data. Conditional random fields offer several advantages over hidden Markov models and
            stochastic grammars for such tasks, including the ability to relax strong independence assumptions made in
            those models. Conditional random fields also avoid a fundamental limitation of maximum entropy Markov models
            (MEMMs) and other discriminative Markov models based on directed graphical models, which can be biased
            towards states with few successor states. We present iterative parameter estimation algorithms for
            conditional random fields and compare the performance of the resulting models to HMMs and MEMMs on synthetic
            and natural-language data.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Lafferty, John, Zhu, Xiaojin, Liu, Yan</authors>
        <title>Kernel Conditional Random Fields: Representation and Clique Selection</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>In The 21st International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML)</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Lafferty, John, Liu, Yan, Zhu, Xiaojin</authors>
        <title>Kernel Conditional Random Fields: Representation, Clique Selection, and Semi-Supervised Learning</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>Technical Report CMU-CS-04-115</journal>
        <abstract>Kernel conditional random fields (KCRFs) are introduced as a framework for discriminative modeling of
            graph-structured data. A representer theorem for conditional graphical models is given which shows how
            kernel conditional random fields arise from risk minimization procedures defined using Mercer kernels on
            labeled graphs. A procedure for greedily selecting cliques in the dual representation is then proposed,
            which allows sparse representations. By incorporating kernels and implicit feature spaces into conditional
            graphical models, the framework enables semi-supervised learning algorithms for structured data through the
            use of graph kernels. The framework and clique selection methods are demonstrated in synthetic data
            experiments, and are also applied to the problem of protein secondary structure prediction.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Lacoste-Julien, Simon</authors>
        <title>Combining SVM with Graphical Models for Supervised Classification: An Introduction to Max-Margin Markov
            Networks
        </title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <abstract>The goal of this paper is to present a survey of the concepts needed to understand the novel
            Max-Margin Markov Networks (M3-net) framework, a new formalism invented by Taskar, Guestrin and Koller which
            combines both the advantages of the graphical models and the Support Vector Machines (SVMs) to solve the
            problem of multi-label multi-class supervised classification. We will compare generative models,
            discriminative graphical models and SVMs for this task, introducing the basic concepts at the same time,
            leading at the end to a presentation of the M3-net paper.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Kumar, Sanjiv, Hebert, Martial</authors>
        <title>Discriminative Fields for Modeling Spatial Dependencies in Natural Images</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>In Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 16 (NIPS 2003), 2004</journal>
        <abstract>In this paper we present Discriminative Random Fields (DRF), a discriminative framework for the
            classification of natural image regions by incorporating neighborhood spatial dependencies in the labels as
            well as the observed data. The proposed model exploits local discriminative models and allows to relax the
            assumption of conditional independence of the observed data given the labels, commonly used in the Markov
            Random Field (MRF) framework. The parameters of the DRF model are learned using penalized maximum
            pseudo-likelihood method. Furthermore, the form of the DRF model allows the MAP inference for binary
            classification problems using the graph min-cut algorithms. The performance of the model was verified on the
            synthetic as well as the real-world images. The DRF model outperforms the MRF model in the experiments.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Kristjansson, Trausti T., Culotta, Aron, Viola, Paul, McCallum, Andrew, McGuinness, Deborah, Ferguson,
            George
        </authors>
        <title>Interactive Information Extraction with Constrained Conditional Random Fields</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>412-418</page>
        <journal>In Proceedings of the Nineteenth National Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI 2004)</journal>
        <abstract>Information Extraction methods can be used to automatically fill-in database forms from unstructured
            data such as Web documents or email. State-of-the-art methods have achieved low error rates but invariably
            make a number of errors. The goal of an interactive information extraction system is to assist the user in
            filling in database fields while giving the user confidence in the integrity of the data. The user is
            presented with an interactive interface that allows both the rapid verification of automatic field
            assignments and the correction of errors. In cases where there are multiple errors, our system takes into
            account user corrections, and immediately propagates these constraints such that other fields are often
            corrected automatically. Linear-chain conditional random fields (CRFs) have been shown to perform well for
            information extraction and other language modelling tasks due to their ability to capture arbitrary,
            overlapping features of the input in a Markov model. We apply this framework with two extensions: a
            constrained Viterbi decoding which finds the optimal field assignments consistent with the fields explicitly
            specified or corrected by the user; and a mechanism for estimating the confidence of each extracted field,
            so that low-confidence extractions can be highlighted. Both of these mechanisms are incorporated in a novel
            user interface for form filling that is intuitive and speeds the entry of data?providing a 23% reduction in
            error due to automated corrections.
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Klinger, Roman, Tomanek, Katrin</authors>
        <title>Classical Probabilistic Models and Conditional Random Fields</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>He, Xuming, Zemel, Richard, Carreira-Perpiñán, Miguel Á.</authors>
        <title>Multiscale Conditional Random Fields for Image Labeling</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>In Proceedings of the 2004 IEEE Computer Society Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition
            (CVPR 2004)
        </journal>
        <abstract>We propose an approach to include contextual features for labeling images, in which each pixel is
            assigned to one of a finite set of labels. The features are incorporated into a probabilistic framework
            which combines the outputs of several components. Components differ in the information they encode. Some
            focus on the image-label mapping, while others focus solely on patterns within the label field. Components
            also differ in their scale, as some focus on fineresolution patterns while others on coarser, more global
            structure. A supervised version of the contrastive divergence algorithm is applied to learn these features
            from labeled image data. We demonstrate performance on two real-world image databases and compare it to a
            classifier and a Markov random field.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Gregory, Michelle L., Altun, Yasemin</authors>
        <title>Using Conditional Random Fields to Predict Pitch Accents in Conversational Speech</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>In Proceedings of the 42nd Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL 2004)
        </journal>
        <abstract>The detection of prosodic characteristics is an important aspect of both speech synthesis and speech
            recognition. Correct placement of pitch accents aids in more natural sounding speech, while automatic
            detection of accents can contribute to better word-level recognition and better textual understanding. In
            this paper we investigate probabilistic, contextual, and phonological factors that influence pitch accent
            placement in natural, conversational speech in a sequence labeling setting. We introduce Conditional Random
            Fields (CRFs) to pitch accent prediction task in order to incorporate these factors efficiently in a
            sequence model. We demonstrate the usefulness and the incremental effect of these factors in a sequence
            model by performing experiments on hand labeled data from the Switchboard Corpus. Our model outperforms the
            baseline and previous models of pitch accent prediction on the Switchboard Corpus.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Dietterich, Thomas G., Ashenfelter, Adam, Bulatov, Yaroslav</authors>
        <title>Training Conditional Random Fields via Gradient Tree Boosting</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>In Proceedings of the Twenty-First International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML 2004)</journal>
        <abstract>Conditional Random Fields (CRFs; Lafferty, McCallum, &amp; Pereira, 2001) provide a flexible and
            powerful model for learning to assign labels to elements of sequences in such applications as part-of-speech
            tagging, text-to-speech mapping, protein and DNA sequence analysis, and information extraction from web
            pages. However, existing learning algorithms are slow, particularly in problems with large numbers of
            potential input features. This paper describes a new method for training CRFs by applying Friedman's (1999)
            gradient tree boosting method. In tree boosting, the CRF potential functions are represented as weighted
            sums of regression trees. Regression trees are learned by stage-wise optimizations similar to Adaboost, but
            with the objective of maximizing the conditional likelihood P(Y|X) of the CRF model. By growing regression
            trees, interactions among features are introduced only as needed, so although the parameter space is
            potentially immense, the search algorithm does not explicitly consider the large space. As a result,
            gradient tree boosting scales linearly in the order of the Markov model and in the order of the feature
            interactions, rather than exponentially like previous algorithms based on iterative scaling and gradient
            descent.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Dietterich, Thomas G.</authors>
        <title>Machine Learning for Sequential Data: A Review</title>
        <year>2002</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the Joint IAPR International Workshop on Structural, Syntactic, and Statistical Pattern
            Recognition; Lecture Notes in Computer Science
        </journal>
        <abstract>Statistical learning problems in many fields involve sequential data. This paper formalizes the
            principal learning tasks and describes the methods that have been developed within the machine learning
            research community for addressing these problems. These methods include sliding window methods, recurrent
            sliding windows, hidden Markov models, conditional random fields, and graph transformer networks. The paper
            also discusses some open research issues.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Culotta, Aron, Kulp, David, McCallum, Andrew</authors>
        <title>Gene Prediction with Conditional Random Fields</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <journal>Technical Report UM-CS-2005-028</journal>
        <abstract>Given a sequence of DNA nucleotide bases, the task of gene prediction is to find subsequences of bases
            that encode proteins. Reasonable performance on this task has been achieved using generatively trained
            sequence models, such as hidden Markov models. We propose instead the use of a discriminitively trained
            sequence model, the conditional random field (CRF). CRFs can naturally incorporate arbitrary,
            non-independent features of the input without making conditional independence assumptions among the
            features. This can be particularly important for gene finding, where including evidence from protein
            databases, EST data, or tiling arrays may improve accuracy. We eval- uate our model on human genomic data,
            and show that CRFs perform better than HMM-based models at incorporating homology evidence from protein
            databases, achieving a 10% reduction in base-level errors.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Bockhorst, Jospeh, Craven, Mark</authors>
        <title>Markov Networks for Detecting Overlapping Elements in Sequence Data</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <journal>In Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems 17 (NIPS 2004)</journal>
        <abstract>Many sequential prediction tasks involve locating instances of pat- terns in sequences. Generative
            probabilistic language models, such as hidden Markov models (HMMs), have been successfully applied to many
            of these tasks. A limitation of these models however, is that they cannot naturally handle cases in which
            pattern instances overlap in arbitrary ways. We present an alternative approach, based on conditional Markov
            networks, that can naturally represent arbitrarily overlapping elements. We show how to efficiently train
            and perform inference with these models. Experimental results from a genomics domain show that our models
            are more accurate at locating instances of overlapping patterns than are baseline models based on HMMs.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Altun, Yasemin, Smola, Alex J., Hofmann, Thomas</authors>
        <title>Exponential Families for Conditional Random Fields</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>In Proceedings of the 20th Conference on Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence (UAI-2004)</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Altun, Yasemin, Hofmann, Thomas</authors>
        <title>Gaussian Process Classification for Segmenting and Annotating Sequences</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>Technical Report CS-04-12</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Altun, Yasemin, Hofmann, Thomas</authors>
        <title>Large Margin Methods for Label Sequence Learning</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <journal>In Proceedings of 8th European Conference on Speech Communication and Technology (EuroSpeech)</journal>
        <abstract>Label sequence learning is the problem of inferring a state sequence from an observation sequence,
            where the state sequence may encode a labeling, annotation or segmentation of the sequence. In this paper we
            give an overview of discriminative methods developed for this problem. Special emphasis is put on large
            margin methods by generalizing multiclass Support Vector Machines and AdaBoost to the case of label
            sequences.An experimental evaluation demonstrates the advantages over classical approaches like Hidden
            Markov Models and the competitiveness with methods like Conditional Random Fields.
        </abstract>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Engin Sezer</authors>
        <title>An Autosegmental Analysis of Compensatory Lengthening in Turkish</title>
        <year>1986</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ozlem Cetinoglu, Kemal Oflazer</authors>
        <title>Morphology-Syntax Interface for Turkish LFG</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <journal>in Proceedings of COLING/ACL 2006</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Fazli Can</authors>
        <title>Turkish information retrieval: Past changes future</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <page>13-22</page>
        <journal>Advances in Information Systems, Proceedings (LECTURE NOTES IN COMPUTER SCIENCE)</journal>
        <volume>4243</volume>
        <abstract>One of the most exciting accomplishments of computer science in the lifetime of this generation is the
            World Wide Web. The Web is a global electronic publishing medium. Its size has been growing with an enormous
            speed for over a decade. Most of its content is objectionable, but it also contains a huge amount of
            valuable information. The Web adds a new dimension to the concept of information explosion and tries to
            solve the very same problem by information retrieval systems known as Web search engines. We briefly review
            the information explosion problem and information retrieval systems, convey the past and state of the art in
            Turkish information retrieval research, illustrate some recent developments, and propose some future actions
            in this research area in Turkey.
        </abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Canan Pembe, Ahmet Celal Cem Say</authors>
        <title>A linguistically motivated information retrieval system for Turkish</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>741-750</page>
        <journal>COMPUTER AND INFORMATION SCIENCES - ISCIS 2004, PROCEEDINGS</journal>
        <volume>3280</volume>
        <abstract>Information retrieval (IR) has become an important application in today's computer world because of
            the great increase in the amount of web-based documents and the widespread use of the Internet. However, the
            classical bag of words approach no longer meets user expectations adequately. In this context, natural
            language processing (NLP) techniques come into mind. In this paper, we investigate the question of whether
            NLP techniques can improve the effectiveness of information retrieval in Turkish. We implemented and tested
            a linguistically motivated information retrieval system, which uses knowledge of the morphological,
            lexico-semantical and syntactical levels of Turkish.
        </abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Dillon, M.</authors>
        <title>Introduction to Modern Information-Retrieval - Salton,G, Mcgill,M</title>
        <year>1983</year>
        <page>402-403</page>
        <journal>Information Processing &amp; Management</journal>
        <number>6</number>
        <volume>19</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Fazl? Can, Seyit Kocberber, Erman Balcik, Cihan Kaynak, Huseyin Cagdas Ocalan, Onur Murat Vursavas
        </authors>
        <title>Information retrieval on Turkish texts</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <page>407-421</page>
        <journal>JOURNAL OF THE AMERICAN SOCIETY FOR INFORMATION SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY</journal>
        <number>3</number>
        <volume>59</volume>
        <abstract>In this study, we investigate information retrieval (IR) on Turkish texts using a large-scale test
            collection that contains 408,305 documents and 72 ad hoc queries. We examine the effects of several stemming
            options and query-document matching functions on retrieval performance. We show that a simple word
            truncation approach, a word truncation approach that uses language-dependent corpus statistics, and an
            elaborate lemmatizer-based stemmer provide similar retrieval effectiveness in Turkish IR. We investigate the
            effects of a range of search conditions on the retrieval performance; these include scalability issues,
            query and document length effects, and the use of stopword list in indexing.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Yiltan Bitirim, Yasar Tonta, Hayri Sever</authors>
        <title>Information Retrieval Effectiveness of Turkish Search Engines</title>
        <year>2002</year>
        <page>93-103</page>
        <journal>ADVANCES IN INFORMATION SYSTEMS</journal>
        <volume>2457</volume>
        <abstract>This is an investigation of information retrieval performance of Turkish search engines with respect
            to precision, normalized recall, coverage and novelty ratios. We defined seventeen query topics for Arabul,
            Arama, Netbul and Superonline. These queries were carefully selected to assess the capability of a search
            engine for handling broad or narrow topic subjects, exclusion of particular information, identifying and
            indexing Turkish characters, retrieval of hub/authoritative pages, stemming of Turkish words, correct
            interpretation of Boolean operators. We classified each document in a retrieval output as being relevant or
            nonrelevant to calculate precision and normalized recall ratios at various cut-off points for each pair of
            query topic and search engine. We found the coverage and novelty ratios for each search engine. We also
            tested how search engines handle meta-tags and dead links. Arama appears to be the best Turkish search
            engine in terms of average precision and normalized recall ratios, and the coverage of Turkish sites.
            Turkish characters (and stemming as well) still cause bottlenecks for Turkish search engines. Superonline
            and Netbul make use of the indexing information in metatag fields to improve retrieval results.
        </abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Yiltan Bitirim, Yasar Tonta, Hayri Sever</authors>
        <title>Apache Mahout - Taste Documentation</title>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <year>Unknown</year>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Gülsen Eryigit, Esref Adali</authors>
        <title>An Affix Stripping Morphological Analyzer For Turkish</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>299-304 910</page>
        <journal>Proceedings of the IASTED International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Applications
        </journal>
        <volume>1-2</volume>
        <abstract>This paper presents the design and the implementation of a morphological analyzer for Turkish. A new
            methodology is proposed for doing the analysis of Turkish words with an affix stripping approach and without
            using any lexicon. The rule-based and agglutinative structure of the language allows Turkish to be modeled
            with finite state machines (FSMs). In contrast to the previous works, in this study, FSMs are formed by
            using the morphotactic rules in reverse order. This paper describes the steps of this new methodology
            including the classification of the suffixes, the generation of the FSMs for each suffix class and their
            unification into a main machine to cooperate in the analysis.
        </abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Stephen, E. Robertson, Karen Sparck, Jones</authors>
        <title>Relevance W eighting of S earch T erms</title>
        <year>1988</year>
        <page>143-160</page>
        <journal>Document R etrieval S ystems</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Christopher D. Manning, Prabhakar Raghavan, Hinrich Schütze</authors>
        <title>Introduction to Information Retrieval</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Karen Sparck Jones</authors>
        <title>Automatic Keyword Classification for Information Retrieval</title>
        <year>1971</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Gwet, Kilem</authors>
        <title>Statistical Tables for Inter-Rater Agreement</title>
        <year>2001</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Gerard, Salton, Chris, Buckley</authors>
        <title>Improving R etrieval P erformance by R elevance F eedback</title>
        <year>1997</year>
        <page>355-364</page>
        <journal>Readings in I nformation R etrieval</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ricardo Baeza-Yates, Berthier Ribeiro-Neto</authors>
        <title>Modern Information Retrieval</title>
        <year>1999</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Gulsen Eryigit, Joakim Nivre, Kemal Oflazer</authors>
        <title>Dependency parsing of turkish</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <page>357-389</page>
        <journal>Comput. Linguist.</journal>
        <number>3</number>
        <volume>34</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Gokhan Tur, Andreas Stolcke, Dilek Hakkani Tur, Elizabeth Shriberg</authors>
        <title>Integrating prosodic and lexical cues for automatic topic segmentation</title>
        <year>2001</year>
        <page>31-57</page>
        <journal>Comput. Linguist.</journal>
        <number>1</number>
        <volume>27</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Gokhan Tur, Dilek Hakkani Tur, Kemal Oflazer</authors>
        <title>A statistical information extraction system for Turkish</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <page>181-210</page>
        <journal>Nat. Lang. Eng.</journal>
        <number>2</number>
        <volume>9</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Zheng-Tao, Yu, Yan-Xia, Qiu, Jin-Hui, Deng, Lu, Han, Cun-Li, Mao, Xiang-Yan, Meng</authors>
        <title>Research on Chinese FAQ Question Answering System in Restricted Domain</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>3927-3932</page>
        <journal>Machine Learning and Cybernetics, 2007 International Conference on</journal>
        <volume>7</volume>
        <abstract>FAQ (frequently-asked question) is a good question and answer model to realize business advisory
            system in restricted domain. A FAQ question answering system model is presented in this paper. With the help
            of the idea of ontology, a knowledge base is constructed in the domain. With the help of language KDML
            (Knowledge Database Mark-up Language) of HowNet,the domain ontology and the relationship of it are defined
            and described, and the fusion of domain knowledge base (domain HowNet) and common knowledge base(HowNet) is
            realized. On this basis, a question similarity calculation method, which makes use of the characteristics of
            the domain question and combines lexical relationship, syntactic interdependent relationship and the
            semantic relationship of domains among question sentences, is implemented. And based on the question
            similarity calculation, retrieval of related question from the candidate question set and extraction of
            answers can be implemented with this method. The result of Yunnan tourism question-answer model experiment
            shows that this method is feasible and effective.
        </abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Deniz Yuret, O zlem Uzuner, Boris Katz</authors>
        <title>Word sense disambiguation for information retrieval</title>
        <year>1999</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the sixteenth national conference on Artificial intelligence</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Deniz Yuret</authors>
        <title>Learning Morphological Disambiguation Rules for Turkish</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <journal>In Proceedings of the Human Language Technology Conference</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Hitay Yiikseker</authors>
        <title>The Multi-purpose Future Morpheme</title>
        <year>2000</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Sheng-Yuan Yang</authors>
        <title>Developing an Ontological FAQ System with FAQ Processing and Ranking Techniques for Ubiquitous Services
        </title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <page>541-546</page>
        <journal>Ubi-Media Computing, 2008 First IEEE International Conference on</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Valentin, Jijkoun, Maarten de, Rijke</authors>
        <title>Retrieving answers from frequently asked questions pages on the web</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 14th ACM international conference on Information and knowledge management</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Robert Underhill</authors>
        <title>Bibliography of Modern Linguistic Work on Turkish</title>
        <year>2000</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Robert Underhill</authors>
        <title>Turkish</title>
        <year>1986</year>
        <page>7-21</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ebru Turker</authors>
        <title>On the Notion of Transitivity in Korean and Turkish</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Umit D. Turan</authors>
        <title>Definite Zero and Overt Objects in Turkish</title>
        <year>20 00</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Umit Deniz Turan</authors>
        <title>Definiteness and Information-Status in Turkish</title>
        <year>1996</year>
        <journal>Proc of 8th International Conference on Turkish Linguistics</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Umit Deniz Turan</authors>
        <title>The Syntactic Properties of Null Objects in Turkish</title>
        <year>1992</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Gokhan Tur</authors>
        <title>A Statistical Information Extraction System for Turkish</title>
        <year>2000</year>
        <journal>Department of Computer Engineering and The Inst?tute of Engineering and Science</journal>
        <volume>Doctor of Philosophy</volume>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Dilek Zeynep Hakkani Tur, Gokhan Tur</authors>
        <title>Statistical Sentence Extraction for Information Distillation</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>IV-1-IV-4</page>
        <journal>IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing ( ICASSP 2007 )</journal>
        <volume>4</volume>
        <abstract>Information distillation aims to extract the most useful pieces of information related to a given
            query from massive, possibly multilingual, audio and textual document sources. One critical component in a
            distillation engine is detecting sentences to be extracted from each relevant document. In this paper, we
            present a statistical sentence extraction approach for distillation. Basically, we frame this tack as a
            classification problem, where each candidate sentence in documents is classified as a relevant to the query
            or not. These documents may be textual or audio format and in a number of languages. For audio documents, we
            use both manual and automatic transcriptions, for non-English documents, we use automatic translations. In
            this work, we use AdaBoost, a discriminative classification method with both lexical and semantic features.
            The results indicate 11%-13% relative improvement over a baseline keyword-spotting-based approach. We also
            show the robustness of our method on the audio subset of the document sources using manual and automatic
            transcriptions
        </abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Dilek Zeynep Hakkani Tur, Kemal Oflazer, Gokhan Tur</authors>
        <title>Statistical M orphological D isambiguation for A gglutinative L anguages</title>
        <year>2002</year>
        <page>381-410</page>
        <journal>Computers and the Humanities</journal>
        <number>4</number>
        <volume>36</volume>
        <abstract>We present statistical models for morphological disambiguation in agglutinative languages, with a
            specific application to Turkish. Turkish presents an interesting problem for statistical models as the
            potential tag set size is very large because of the productive derivational morphology. We propose to handle
            this by breaking up the morhosyntactic tags into inflectional groups, each of which contains the
            inflectional features for each (intermediate) derived form. Our statistical models score the probability of
            each morhosyntactic tag by considering statistics over the individual inflectional groups and surface roots
            in trigram models. Among the four models that we have developed and tested, the simplest model ignoring the
            local morphotactics within words performs the best. Our best trigram model performs with 93.95% accuracy on
            our test data getting all the morhosyntactic and semantic features correct. If we are just interested in
            syntactically relevant features and ignore a very small set of semantic features, then the accuracy
            increases to 95.07%.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Dilek Zeynep Hakkani Tur</authors>
        <title>Statistical Modeling of Agglutinative Languages</title>
        <year>2000</year>
        <journal>Department of Computer Engineering and The Inst?tute of Engineering and Science</journal>
        <volume>Doctor of Philosophy</volume>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Dilek Zeynep Hakkani Tur</authors>
        <title>Generation Turkish Noun Phrases</title>
        <year>1995</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Yasar Tonta</authors>
        <title>Bilgi Erisim Sorunu</title>
        <year>2001</year>
        <journal>Eprints in Library and Information Science Homepage(Hatay bildiri)</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Serafettin Tasci, Mustafa Gungor, Tunga Gungor</authors>
        <title>Compiling a Turkish-English Bilingual Corpus and Developing an Algorithm for Sentence Alignment</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <page>291-296</page>
        <journal>Third International Bulgarian-Turkish Conference on Computer Science, October 2006, Istanbul</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Stoyanchev, S., Tur, G., Hakkani-Tur, D.</authors>
        <title>Name-aware speech recognition for interactive question answering</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <page>5113-5116</page>
        <journal>Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing, 2008. ICASSP 2008. IEEE International Conference on</journal>
        <abstract>In this work we show how interactivity in a voice-enabled question answering application may improve
            speech recognition. We allow the user to provide a target named entity before asking the question. Then we
            build a named entity specific language model using the documents containing the named entity. The
            question-specific model is obtained by merging the named entity specific model with the model built on a set
            of questions. We present a set of experiments using the TREC question set on the AQUAINT corpus. The
            question-specific language model is compared with the baseline model built by merging a model of the AQUAINT
            corpus and past TREC questions. The question-specific model achieves 32.2% reduction in word error rate from
            the baseline using the questions where pronominal references are resolved.
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Svetlana Stenchikova, Dilek Hakkani Tur, Gokhan Tur</authors>
        <title>QASR: question answering using semantic roles for speech interface</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <journal>In INTERSPEECH-2006, paper 2054-Tue2CaP.10.</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Svetlana Stenchikova, Dilek Hakkani Tur, Gokhan Tur</authors>
        <title>QASR:Spoken Question Answering Using Semantic Role Labeling</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <journal>in ASRU</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Spink, A., Yang, Y., Jansen, J., Nykanen, P., Lorence, D. P., Ozmutlu, S., Ozmutlu, H. C.</authors>
        <title>A study of medical and health queries to web search engines</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>44-51</page>
        <journal>Health Info Libr J</journal>
        <number>1</number>
        <volume>21</volume>
        <abstract>This paper reports findings from an analysis of medical or health queries to different web search
            engines. We report results: (i). comparing samples of 10000 web queries taken randomly from 1.2 million
            query logs from the AlltheWeb.com and Excite.com commercial web search engines in 2001 for medical or health
            queries, (ii). comparing the 2001 findings from Excite and AlltheWeb.com users with results from a previous
            analysis of medical and health related queries from the Excite Web search engine for 1997 and 1999, and
            (iii). medical or health advice-seeking queries beginning with the word 'should'. Findings suggest: (i). a
            small percentage of web queries are medical or health related, (ii). the top five categories of medical or
            health queries were: general health, weight issues, reproductive health and puberty, pregnancy/obstetrics,
            and human relationships, and (iii). over time, the medical and health queries may have declined as a
            proportion of all web queries, as the use of specialized medical/health websites and e-commerce-related
            queries has increased. Findings provide insights into medical and health-related web querying and suggests
            some implications for the use of the general web search engines when seeking medical/health information.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Spink, Amanda, Ozmutlu, H. Cenk, Ozmutlu, Seda</authors>
        <title>Multitasking Information Seeking and Searching</title>
        <year>2002</year>
        <page>639</page>
        <journal>Journal of the American Society for Information Science &amp; Technology</journal>
        <number>8</number>
        <volume>53</volume>
        <abstract>Examines the multitasking information seeking behavior on searching processes. Prevalence of
            multitasking seeking and searching over multiple studies in different information environments;
            Characteristics of multitasking information seeking with single-topic search sessions; Factors indicating a
            topic change during user search session.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Spink, Amanda, Cenk Ozmutlu, H., Lorence, Daniel P.</authors>
        <title>Web searching for sexual information: an exploratory study</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>113</page>
        <journal>Information Processing &amp; Management</journal>
        <number>1</number>
        <volume>40</volume>
        <abstract>Sexuality on the Internet takes many forms and channels, including chat rooms discussions, accessing
            Websites or searching Web search engines for sexual materials. The study of Web sexual queries provides
            insight into sexual-related information-seeking behavior, of value to Web users and providers alike. We
            qualitatively analyzed 58,027 queries from a log of 1,025,910 Excite Web user queries from 1999. We found
            that sexual and non-sexual-related queries exhibited differences in session duration, query outcomes, and
            search term choices. Implications for sexual information seeking and Web systems are discussed. [Copyright
            2004 Elsevier]
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Aysin Solak, Kemal Oflazer</authors>
        <title>A Finite State Machine for Turkish Syllable Structure Analysis</title>
        <year>1990</year>
        <journal>Proc. of 5. ISCIS</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>E Sneiders</authors>
        <title>Automated FAQ Answering: Continued Experience with Shallow Language Understanding</title>
        <year>1999</year>
        <journal>Proc. of the 1999 AAAI Fall Symp., AAAI</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Sheng-Yuan, Yang, Fang-Chen, Chuang, Cheng-Seen, Ho</authors>
        <title>Ontology-supported FAQ processing and ranking techniques</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>233-251</page>
        <journal>J. Intell. Inf. Syst.</journal>
        <number>3</number>
        <volume>28</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Sheng-Yuan, Yang</authors>
        <title>A new ontology-supported interface agent</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>1-4</page>
        <journal>TENCON 2007 - 2007 IEEE Region 10 Conference</journal>
        <abstract>In this paper, an Interface Agent which worked as an assistant between the users and FAQ systems to
            retrieve FAQs on the domain of Personal Computer was illustrated. Specifically, how ontology helped
            interface agents to provide better FAQ services and related algorithms described in details. Our preliminary
            experimentation demonstrated that user intention and focus of up to eighty percent of the user queries can
            be correctly understood by the system, and accordingly provided the query solutions with higher user
            satisfaction.
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Engin Sezer</authors>
        <title>On Non-Final Stress in Turkish</title>
        <year>1981</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Engin Sezer</authors>
        <title>Some Obsevations on The Genitive Phrases In Turkish Nominalizations</title>
        <year>1972</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Hayri Sever, Yasar Tonta</authors>
        <title>Truncation of Content Terms for Turkish</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <journal>Eprints in Library and Information Science Homepage</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Hayri Sever, Yiltan Bitirim</authors>
        <title>FindStem: Analysis and evaluation of a Turkish stemming algorithm</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <journal>STRING PROCESSING AND INFORMATION RETRIEVAL, PROCEEDINGS</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Hayri Sever, Fuat Akal, Guven Kose</authors>
        <title>Kavram Tabanl? Bilgi Geri Getirim Yakla??m?</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <journal>Bilgi dünyas? (Unak) Cilt8 Say? 1</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Metin S enkal, Tunga Gungor, Onur Kardes</authors>
        <title>An Approach for Machine Translation Between Turkish and Spanish</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <page>471-473</page>
        <journal>International Twelfth Turkish Symposium on Artificial Intelligence and Neural Networks (TAINN 2003),
            Vol.E-5, July 2003, Çanakkale
        </journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Onur T. Sehitoglu, H. Cem Bozsahin</authors>
        <title>Morphological Productivity in the Lexicon</title>
        <year>1996</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Seda, Ozmutlu, Huseyin, C. Ozmutlu, Buket, Buyuk</authors>
        <title>Using conditional probabilities for automatic new topic identification</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>491-515</page>
        <journal>Online Information Review</journal>
        <number>4</number>
        <volume>31</volume>
        <abstract>Purpose - One of the most important dimensions of search engine user information seeking behaviour is
            content-based behaviour. One of the main elements in developing a personalised intelligent search engine is
            new topic identification. The purpose of this study is to perform automatic new topic identification in
            search engine transaction logs using conditional probabilities of new topic arrivals.
            Design/methodology/approach - Sample data logs from FAST (currently owned by Yahoo!) and Excite (currently
            owned by IAC Search &amp; Media) are used in the study. Conditional probabilities of new topic arrivals and
            topic continuations given query category are used to estimate new topic arrivals. Findings - The findings of
            this study show that the conditional probability approach reduced overestimation of topic shifts, increasing
            some performance measures to their highest ever value compared to previous studies. A straightforward
            procedure such as the conditional probability approach can be as successful as, and for some measures more
            successful than, more complex methods applied in previous automatic new topic identification studies.
            Originality/value - A straightforward procedure that can enable fast automatic new topic identification, a
            problem not yet solved, and an important step towards personalised search engines. [ABSTRACT FROM AUTHOR]
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Seda, Ozmutlu, Fatih, Cavdur</authors>
        <title>Neural network applications for automatic new topic identification</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <page>34-53</page>
        <journal>Online Information Review</journal>
        <number>1</number>
        <volume>29</volume>
        <abstract>Purpose - This study aims to propose an artificial neural network to identify automatically topic
            changes in a user session by using the statistical characteristics of queries, such as time intervals and
            query reformulation patterns. Design/methodology/approach - A sample data log from the Norwegian search
            engine FAST (currently owned by Overture) is selected to train the neural network and then the neural
            network is used to identify topic changes in the data log. Findings - A total of 98.4 percent of topic
            shifts and 86.6 percent of topic continuations were estimated correctly. Originality/value - Content
            analysis of search engine user queries is an important task, since successful exploitation of the content of
            queries can result in the design of efficient information retrieval algorithms for search engines, which can
            offer custom-tailored services to the web user. Identification of topic changes within a user search session
            is a key issue in the content analysis of search engine user queries. [ABSTRACT FROM AUTHOR]
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>I. Hikmet Sebiiktekin</authors>
        <title>Morphotactics of Turkish Verb Suffixation</title>
        <year>1974</year>
        <journal>Humaniter Sciences</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Johannes van Schaaik</authors>
        <title>Studies in Turkish Grammar</title>
        <year>2001</year>
        <journal>The Bosphorus Papers</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Bilge Say, Deniz Zeyrek, Kemal Oflazer, Umut Ozge</authors>
        <title>Development of a Corpus and a Treebank for Present-day Written Turkish</title>
        <year>2002</year>
        <journal>11th International Conference on Turkish Linguistics</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ahmet Celal Cem Say, Ozlem Cetinoglu, Seniz Demir, Fatih Ogun</authors>
        <title>A Natural Language Processing Infrastructure for Turkish</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>in Proceedings of COLING 2004, August 2004, Geneva, Switzerland</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Beatrice Santorini</authors>
        <title>Part-of-Speech Tagging Guidelines forthe Penn Treebank Project</title>
        <year>1990</year>
        <journal>Department of Computer and Information Science</journal>
        <volume>Technical Report No. MS-CIS-90-47</volume>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Hasim Sak, Tunga Gungor, Murat Saraclar</authors>
        <title>Morphological Disambiguation of Turkish Text with Perceptron Algorithm</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <journal>8th International Conference on Intelligent Text Processing and Computational Linguistics (CicLing
            2007), Ed. A.Gelbukh, February 2007, Mexico City - LNCS (Lecture Notes in Computer Science), Vol.4394, 2007,
            p.107-118, Springer-Verlag, Berlin Heidelberg
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Hasim Sak, Tunga Gungor, Yasar Safkan</authors>
        <title>A Corpus-Based Concatenative Speech Synthesis System for Turkish</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <page>209-223</page>
        <journal>Turkish Journal of Electrical Engineering and Computer Sciences</journal>
        <number>2</number>
        <volume>14</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Hasim Sak, Tunga Gungor, Yasar Safkan</authors>
        <title>Generation of Synthetic Speech from Turkish Text</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <journal>13th European Signal Processing Conference (EUSIPCO 2005), September 2005, Antalya</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Robin, D. Burke, Kristian, J. Hammond, Vladimir, A. Kulyukin, Steven, L. Lytinen, N. Tomuro, S.
            Schoenberg
        </authors>
        <title>Question Answering from Frequently Asked Question Files: Experiences with the FAQ Finder System</title>
        <year>1997</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Robin, D. Burke, Kristian, J. Hammond, Benjamin, C. Young</authors>
        <title>The FindMe Approach to Assisted Browsing</title>
        <year>1997</year>
        <page>32-40</page>
        <journal>IEEE Expert: Intelligent Systems and Their Applications</journal>
        <number>4</number>
        <volume>12</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Fabien Reniers, Sarah D. Kennelly</authors>
        <title>Resolution of the Distributive - Cumulative Interplay</title>
        <year>1999</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Canan Pembe, Tunga Gungor</authors>
        <title>Automated Query-Biased and Structure-Preserving Text Summarization on Web Documents</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <journal>International Symposium on Innovations in Intelligent Systems and Applications (INISTA 2007), June
            2007, Istanbul
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>A. Sumru Ozsoy, Eser E. Taylan</authors>
        <title>Turkce'de Ad Obeginin Ic Yapisi</title>
        <year>1992</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>A. Sumru Ozsoy</authors>
        <title>Locative inversion, VP adjunction and Turkish relativisation</title>
        <year>1998</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>A. Sumru Ozsoy</authors>
        <title>Dependencies in Turkish</title>
        <year>1990</year>
        <journal>Current Issues in Turkish Linguistics 1 ,ed. B.Rona,139-158</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ozmutlu, Seda, Spink, Amanda, Ozmutlu, H. Cenk, Toms, Elaine G.</authors>
        <title>Multimedia Web searching trends</title>
        <year>2002</year>
        <page>403-408</page>
        <journal>Information, Connections, and Community (Proceedings of the 65th Conference of the American Society for
            Information Science &amp; Technology)
        </journal>
        <abstract>Based on analysis of very large Web query data sets with more than 1 million queries each, reports
            findings on Web multimedia searching by the Excite and FAST search engines in 2001. Finds that: (1) some
            differences exist between the Excite and FAST multimedia Web searches; (2) FAST users submit more multimedia
            queries but fewer audio-related queries; (3) FAST users take more time with queries and sessions compared
            with Excite users, but spend less time on audio queries; and (4) Excite users submit longer and more complex
            queries than FAST users. Since the Excite search engine is US-based and the FAST search engine Norway-based,
            concludes that some differences in the Web search behavior can be attributed to differences between US and
            European users. Proceeding Published by Information Today, Inc., 2002
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ozmutlu, Seda, Spink, Amanda, Ozmutlu, Huseyin C.</authors>
        <title>A day in the life of Web searching: an exploratory study</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>319</page>
        <journal>Information Processing &amp; Management</journal>
        <number>2</number>
        <volume>40</volume>
        <abstract>Understanding Web searching behavior is important in developing more successful and cost-efficient Web
            search engines. We provide results from a comparative time-based Web study of US-based Excite and
            Norwegian-based Fast Web search logs, exploring variations in user searching related to changes in time of
            the day. Findings suggest: (1) fluctuations in Web user behavior over the day, (2) user investigations of
            query results are much longer, and submission of queries and number of users are much higher in the
            mornings, and (3) some query characteristics, including terms per query and query reformulation, remain
            steady throughout the day. Implications and further research are discussed. [Copyright 2004 Elsevier]
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ozmutlu, Seda, Spink, Amanda, Ozmutlu, Huseyin C.</authors>
        <title>Multimedia Web searching trends: 1997-2001</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <page>611</page>
        <journal>Information Processing &amp; Management</journal>
        <number>4</number>
        <volume>39</volume>
        <abstract>Multimedia is proliferating on Web sites, as the Web continues to enhance the integration of
            multimedia and textual information. In this paper we examine trends in multimedia Web searching by Excite
            users from 1997 to 2001. Results from an analysis of 1,025,910 Excite queries from 2001 are compared to
            similar Excite datasets from 1997 to 1999. Findings include: (1) queries per multimedia session have
            decreased since 1997 as a proportion of general queries due to the introduction of multimedia buttons near
            the query box, (2) multimedia queries identified are longer than non-multimedia queries, and (3) audio
            queries are more prevalent than image or video queries in identified multimedia queries. Overall, we see
            multimedia Web searching undergoing major changes as Web content and searching evolves. [Copyright 2003
            Elsevier]
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ozmutlu, Seda, Cosar, Gencer C.</authors>
        <title>Analyzing the results of automatic new topic identification</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <page>466-487</page>
        <journal>Library Hi Tech</journal>
        <number>3</number>
        <volume>26</volume>
        <abstract>Purpose -- Identification of topic changes within a user search session is a key issue in content
            analysis of search engine user queries. Recently, various studies have focused on new topic
            identification/session identification of search engine transaction logs, and several problems regarding the
            estimation of topic shifts and continuations were observed in these studies. This study aims to analyze the
            reasons for the problems that were encountered as a result of applying automatic new topic identification.
            Design/methodology/approach -- Measures, such as cleaning the data of common words and analyzing the errors
            of automatic new topic identification, are applied to eliminate the problems in estimating topic shifts and
            continuations. Findings -- The findings show that the resulting errors of automatic new topic identification
            have a pattern, and further research is required to improve the performance of automatic new topic
            identification. Originality/value -- Improving the performance of automatic new topic identification would
            be valuable to search engine designers, so that they can develop new clustering and query recommendation
            algorithms, as well as custom-tailored graphical user interfaces for search engine users. [ABSTRACT FROM
            AUTHOR]
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ozmutlu, Seda</authors>
        <title>Automatic new topic identification using multiple linear regression</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <page>934-950</page>
        <journal>Information Processing &amp; Management</journal>
        <number>4</number>
        <volume>42</volume>
        <abstract>The purpose of this study is to provide automatic new topic identification of search engine query
            logs, and estimate the effect of statistical characteristics of search engine queries on new topic
            identification. By applying multiple linear regression and multi-factor ANOVA on a sample data log from the
            Excite search engine, we demonstrated that the statistical characteristics of Web search queries, such as
            time interval, search pattern and position of a query in a user session, are effective on shifting to a new
            topic. Multiple linear regression is also a successful tool for estimating topic shifts and continuations.
            The findings of this study provide statistical proof for the relationship between the non-semantic
            characteristics of Web search queries and the occurrence of topic shifts and continuations. [Copyright 2006
            Elsevier]
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ozmutlu, H. Cenk, Cavdur, Fatih, Ozmutlu, Seda</authors>
        <title>Cross-validation of neural network applications for automatic new topic identification</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <page>339-362</page>
        <journal>Journal of the American Society for Information Science &amp; Technology</journal>
        <number>3</number>
        <volume>59</volume>
        <abstract>The purpose of this study is to provide results from experiments designed to investigate the
            cross-validation of an artificial neural network application to automatically identify topic changes in Web
            search engine user sessions by using data logs of different Web search engines for training and testing the
            neural network. Sample data logs from the FAST and Excite search engines are used in this study. The results
            of the study show that identification of topic shifts and continuations on a particular Web search engine
            user session can be achieved with neural networks that are trained on a different Web search engine data
            log. Although FAST and Excite search engine users differ with respect to some user characteristics (e.g.,
            number of queries per session, number of topics per session), the results of this study demonstrate that
            both search engine users display similar characteristics as they shift from one topic to another during a
            single search session. The key finding of this study is that a neural network that is trained on a selected
            data log could be universal; that is, it can be applicable on all Web search engine transaction logs
            regardless of the source of the training data log. [ABSTRACT FROM AUTHOR]
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ozmutlu, H. Cenk, Cavdur, Fatih</authors>
        <title>Application of automatic topic identification on Excite Web search engine data logs</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <page>1243-1262</page>
        <journal>Information Processing &amp; Management</journal>
        <number>5</number>
        <volume>41</volume>
        <abstract>The analysis of contextual information in search engine query logs enhances the understanding of Web
            users' search patterns. Obtaining contextual information on Web search engine logs is a difficult task,
            since users submit few number of queries, and search multiple topics. Identification of topic changes within
            a search session is an important branch of search engine user behavior analysis. The purpose of this study
            is to investigate the properties of a specific topic identification methodology in detail, and to test its
            validity. The topic identification algorithm's performance becomes doubtful in various cases. These cases
            are explored and the reasons underlying the inconsistent performance of automatic topic identification are
            investigated with statistical analysis and experimental design techniques. [ABSTRACT FROM AUTHOR]
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Levent Ozgur, Tunga Gungor, Fikret Gurgen</authors>
        <title>Adaptive Anti-Spam Filtering for Agglutinative Languages: A Special Case for Turkish</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>1819-1831</page>
        <journal>Pattern Recognition Letters</journal>
        <number>16</number>
        <volume>25</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Levent Ozgur, Tunga Gungor, Fikret Gurgen</authors>
        <title>Adaptive Turkish Anti-Spam Filtering</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <page>453-455</page>
        <journal>International Twelfth Turkish Symposium on Artificial Intelligence and Neural Networks (TAINN 2003)
        </journal>
        <volume>E-5</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Arzucan Ozgur, Levent Ozgur, Tunga Gungor, P.Yolum, T.Gungor, F.Gurgen, C.Ozturan</authors>
        <title>Text Categorization with Class-Based and Corpus-Based Keyword Selection</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <journal>20th International Symposium on Computer and Information Sciences (ISCIS 2005)</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Gorkem Ozbek, Siddharth Jonathan</authors>
        <title>TURKALATOR, A Suite of Tools for Augmenting English-to-Turkish Statistical Machine Translation</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <journal>Natural Language Processing Final Project</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Kemal Oflazer, Gokhan Tur</authors>
        <title>Morphological disambiguation by voting constraints</title>
        <year>1997</year>
        <journal>In Proceedings of the 35th Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL97,
            EACL97)
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Kemal Oflazer, Dilek Zeynep Hakkani Tur, Gokhan Tur</authors>
        <title>Design for a Turkish Treebank</title>
        <year>1999</year>
        <journal>in the Proceedings of Workshop on Linguistically Interpreted Corpora, at EACL'99, June 12 1999, Bergen,
            Norway.
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Kemal Oflazer, Bilge Say, Dilek Zeynep Hakkani Tur, Gokhan Tur, Anne Abeille</authors>
        <title>Building a Turkish Treebank</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <journal>Building and Using Parsed Corpora</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Kemal Oflazer, Ilker Kuruoz</authors>
        <title>Tagging and M orphological D isambiguation of T urkish T ext</title>
        <year>1994</year>
        <page>144-149</page>
        <journal>In Proceedings of the 4th Applied Natural Language Processing Conference</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Kemal Oflazer, Ozlem Cetinoglu, Bilge Say</authors>
        <title>Integrating Morphology with Multiword Expression Processing in Turkish</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>in Proceedings of the ACL 2004 Workshop on Multiword Expressions: Integrating Processing, July 2004,
            Barcelona, Spain
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Kemal Oflazer, Ozlem Cetinoglu, Orhan Bilgin, Bilge Say</authors>
        <title>A Preprocessor for Turkish Text Analysis</title>
        <year>October 2004</year>
        <journal>Lecture Notes in Computer Science 3280 -- Proceedings ISCIS'04</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Kemal Oflazer, Cem Bozsahin, Elvan Gocmen, Okan Yilmaz, Tolga Yildirim, Onur Sehitoglu</authors>
        <title>Lexicon Design</title>
        <year>2000</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Oflazer, K.</authors>
        <title>Dependency parsing with an extended finite-state approach</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <page>515-544</page>
        <journal>Computational Linguistics</journal>
        <number>4</number>
        <volume>29</volume>
        <abstract>This article presents a dependency parsing scheme using an extended finite-state approach. The parser
            augments input representation with channels so that links representing syntactic dependency relations among
            words can be accommodated and iterates on the input a number of times to arrive at a fixed point.
            Intermediate configurations violating various constraints of projective dependency representations such as
            no crossing links and no independent items except sentential head are filtered via finite-state filters. We
            have applied the parser to dependency parsing of Turkish.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Kemal Oflazer</authors>
        <title>Two-level description of Turkish morphology</title>
        <year>1994</year>
        <page>137-148</page>
        <journal>Literary and Linguistic Computing, 8(3), 1993</journal>
        <number>2</number>
        <volume>9</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Kemal Oflazer</authors>
        <title>Two-level description of Turkish morphology</title>
        <year>1993</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the sixth conference on European chapter of the Association for Computational
            Linguistics
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Rabia Nuray, Fazl? Can</authors>
        <title>Automatic ranking of information retrieval systems using data fusion</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <journal>Information Processing and Management</journal>
        <number>3</number>
        <volume>42</volume>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Rabia Nuray, Fazl? Can</authors>
        <title>Automatic ranking of retrieval systems in imperfect environments</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <page>379?380</page>
        <journal>In Proceedings of the 26th ACM SIGIR conference</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Hasan Mesut Meral, Emre Sevinc, Ersin Unkar, Bulent Sankur, Sumru Ozsoy, Tunga Gungor</authors>
        <title>T ü rkce Metin Damgalama: Sozdizimsel bir Model</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <journal>IEEE 15th Sinyal Isleme ve Iletisim Uygulamalari Kurultayi (SIU 2007)</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Hasan Mesut Meral, Emre Sevinc, Ersin Unkar, Bulent Sankur, Sumru Ozsoy, Tunga Gungor</authors>
        <title>Syntactic Tools for Text Watermarking</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <journal>19th Annual Symposium on Electronic Imaging: Security, Stenography, and Watermarking of Multimedia
            Contents
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Astrid MenzMainz</authors>
        <title>Gagauz right-branching propositions introduced by the element ani</title>
        <year>1996</year>
        <journal>8th International Conference on Turkish Linguistics</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Murat Kumral</authors>
        <title>Infl and Agreement in Turkish Subordinate Clauses</title>
        <year>1993</year>
        <journal>The Proceedings of the Twelfth West Coast Conference onFormal Linguistics</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Jaklin Kornfilt</authors>
        <title>Some Syntactic and Morphological Properties of Relative Clauses in Turkish</title>
        <year>2000</year>
        <journal>Syntax of Relative Clauses</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Jaklin Kornfilt</authors>
        <title>On rightward movement in Turkish</title>
        <year>1998</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Jaklin Kornfilt</authors>
        <title>Turkish and Configurationality</title>
        <year>1990</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Jaklin Kornfilt</authors>
        <title>NP- Deletion and Case Marking in Turkish</title>
        <year>1988</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ilker Kocabas, Taner Kisla, Bahar Karaoglan</authors>
        <title>Zipf ' s law of burstiness in Turkish: The length of intervals between repetitions</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>1-3</page>
        <journal>Computer and Information Sciences, 2007. ISCIS 2007. 22nd International International Symposium on
        </journal>
        <abstract>Zipf law of burstiness of content words is being less studied than his laws that describe the relation
            between the rank and the frequency of words. Zipf counted the number of intervals of the same length between
            the repetitions of the words belonging to the same frequency class and on a 260,000 word English corpus
            empirically showed that the interval size, I, between each occurrence of a word is inversely proportional to
            the number of intervals having that size: F a I p, where p varied between 1 and 1.3. In this study we
            investigated the validity of the law of burstiness on a Turkish corpus of size 55,000 and found p varying
            between 0.5 and 0.8.
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ayhan A. Koc</authors>
        <title>THE ACQUISITION OF ASPECT AND MODALITY : The case of past reference in Turkish</title>
        <year>1988</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Seda Kesen, Canan Senol, Zehra Yanar</authors>
        <title>Google Scholar ve Scirus Arama Motorlar ?nda Türkçe Anahtar Sözcüklerle Yap?lan Aramalar Üzerine Bir
            De?erlendirme
        </title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <journal>De ?i?en Dünyada Bilgi Yönetimi Sempozyumu</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Celia Kerslake</authors>
        <title>Future Time Reference In Turkish Subordinate Clauses</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Sarah D. Kennely</authors>
        <title>The Syntax of the P-Focus Position in Turkish</title>
        <year>1999</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Sarah D. Kennely</authors>
        <title>Reciprocity In Turkish Evidence Against AGR as a Definition of Finiteness</title>
        <year>1992</year>
        <journal>The Proceedings of the Tenth West Coast Confirenee on Formal Linguistics. Stanford Linguistic Society
            pp.269-282
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Kathol, A., Tur, G.</authors>
        <title>Extracting question/answer pairs in multi-party meetings</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <page>5053-5056</page>
        <journal>Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing, 2008. ICASSP 2008. IEEE International Conference on</journal>
        <abstract>Understanding multi-party meetings involves tasks such as dialog act segmentation and tagging, action
            item extraction, and summarization. In this paper we introduce a new task for multi-party meetings:
            extracting question/answer pairs. This is a practical application for further processing such as
            summarization. We propose a method based on discriminative classification of individual sentences as
            questions and answers via lexical, speaker, and dialog act tag information, followed by a contextual
            optimization via Markov models. Our results indicate that it is possible to outperform a non-trivial
            baseline using dialog act tag information. More specifically, our method achieves a 13% relative improvement
            over the baseline for the task of detecting answers in meetings.
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Onur Kardes, Tunga Gungor, Ege Kipman</authors>
        <title>Bir Uygulama Alan?nda Türkçe Metnin Anlambilimsel Gösterimi</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <journal>Akademik Bilisim Konferansi, Çukurova Üniversitesi, February 2003, Adana</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ellen Kaisse</authors>
        <title>Locating Turkish Devocing</title>
        <year>1986</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of WCCFL 5</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Jui-Feng, Yeh, Chung-Hsien, Wu, Ming-Jun, Chen</authors>
        <title>Ontology-based speech act identification in a bilingual dialog system using partial pattern trees</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <page>684-694</page>
        <journal>J. Am. Soc. Inf. Sci. Technol.</journal>
        <number>5</number>
        <volume>59</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Camacho J., Hill V., Hill J. T</authors>
        <title>Squibs and Discussion</title>
        <year>20 00</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Sharon Inkelas, Aylin Kiintay, C. Orhan Orgun</authors>
        <title>Turkish Electronic Living Lexicon (TEEL)</title>
        <year>2000</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Bahar Ilgen, Bahar Karaoglan</authors>
        <title>Investigation of Zipf ' s ' law-of-meaning ' on Turkish corpora</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>1-6</page>
        <journal>Computer and Information Sciences, 2007. ISCIS 2007. 22nd International International Symposium on
        </journal>
        <abstract>Zipf's law-of-meaning states that the number of meanings of a word is related to its frequency. Words
            that are seen more frequently tend to have more meanings than the ones that are seen less frequently. This
            law, like the other Zipfian laws is consistent with the principal of least effort. In this study we hope to
            establish a basis for the number of meanings a word can attain in Turkish with respect to its frequency in a
            document. Zipfian parameters are derived from two Turkish corpora on which the meanings are labeled. It is
            hoped that the results of this study contributes in resolving ambiguity of word senses in Turkish.
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Van Der Hulst, Van De Weijer</authors>
        <title>Topics in Phonology</title>
        <year>1991</year>
        <page>13-15</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Berly Hoffman, Umit Deniz Turan</authors>
        <title>Word Order and Centering in Turkish</title>
        <year>1993</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Beryl Hoffman, Umit Deniz Turan</authors>
        <title>Scranbling in Turkish</title>
        <year>1991</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 15th annual Penn Linguistics Colloquium</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Harksoo, Kim, Jungyun, Seo</authors>
        <title>Cluster-Based FAQ Retrieval Using Latent Term Weights</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <page>58-65</page>
        <number>2</number>
        <volume>23</volume>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Harksoo, Kim, Jungyun, Seo</authors>
        <title>High-performance FAQ retrieval using an automatic clustering method of query logs</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <page>650-661</page>
        <journal>Inf. Process. Manage.</journal>
        <number>3</number>
        <volume>42</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Hammond, K., Burke, R., Schmitt, K.</authors>
        <title>A Case-Based Approach to Knowledge Navigation</title>
        <year>199 6</year>
        <page>125-136</page>
        <journal>In Case-Based Reasoning: Experiences, Lessons, &amp; Future Directions</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>K. Hammond, R. Burke, C. Martin, S. Lytinen</authors>
        <title>FAQ finder: a case-based approach to knowledge navigation</title>
        <year>1995</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 11th Conference on Artificial Intelligence for Applications</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Geoffrey Haig</authors>
        <title>On the interaction of morphological and syntactic ergativity:Lessons from Kurdish</title>
        <year>1998</year>
        <journal>Lingua</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>G. Haig</authors>
        <title>The Dative as Default Case in Turkish</title>
        <year>1997</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the VIIIth International Conference on Turkish Linguistics</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Tunga Gungor, Selahattin Kuru</authors>
        <title>Representation of Turkish Morphology in ATN</title>
        <year>1993</year>
        <journal>International Second Turkish Symposium on Artificial Intelligence and Artificial Neural Networks (TAINN
            1993), 1993, Istanbul, p.94-104
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Tunga Gungor</authors>
        <title>Muhakeme Yurutme ve Karar Vermede Bulussal Yontemler</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <journal>Bilgi Isleyen Makina Olarak Beyin, December 2005, Istanbul</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Tunga Gungor</authors>
        <title>Generation of Sentence Parse Trees Using Parts of Speech</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>27th German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI 2004), Eds. S.Biundo, T.Frühwirth and G.Palm,
            September 2004, Ulm - LNAI (Lecture Notes in Artificial Intelligence), Vol.3238, 2004, p.56-66,
            Springer-Verlag, Berlin Heidelberg
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Tunga Gungor</authors>
        <title>Lexical and Morphological Statistics for Turkish</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <journal>International Twelfth Turkish Symposium on Artificial Intelligence and Neural Networks (TAINN 2003),
            Vol.E-5, July 2003, Çanakkale, p.409-412
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Tunga Gungor</authors>
        <title>An Approach for Generating Sentence Parse Trees Based on Proximity Values</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <page>530-532</page>
        <journal>International Twelfth Turkish Symposium on Artificial Intelligence and Neural Networks (TAINN 2003),
            Vol.E-5, July 2003, Çanakkale
        </journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Onur Gungor, Tunga Gungor</authors>
        <title>T ü rkce i ç in Bilgisayarla ?? lenebilir Sözlük Kullanarak Kavramlar Aras ? ndaki ?li? kilerin
            Belirlenmesi
        </title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <journal>Bilgisayar Bilimleri ve Mühendisligi, TBV Pub. ,</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Asli Goksel</authors>
        <title>On the Asymmetries between Verbal Forms in Turkish and Yakut</title>
        <year>1996</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Asli Goksel</authors>
        <title>Linearity, focus and the postverbal position in Turkish</title>
        <year>1995</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Elvan Gocmen, Onur Sehitoglu, Cem Bozsahin</authors>
        <title>An Outline of Turkish Syntax</title>
        <year>1995</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Gulsen Eryigit</authors>
        <title>ITU Validation Set for Metu-Sabanc i Turkish Treebank</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Gulsen Eryigit</authors>
        <title>ITU Treebank Annotation Tool</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>117--120</page>
        <journal>Proceedings of the Linguistic Annotation Workshop</journal>
        <volume>June</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Eser Erguvanli</authors>
        <title>An Odd Case in the Causative Construction of Turkish</title>
        <year>1979</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>I lknur Durgar El-Kahlout, Kemal Oflazer</authors>
        <title>Use of Wordnet for Retrieving Words from Their Meanings</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>118-123</page>
        <journal>in Proceedings of the Global WordNet Conference (GWC)</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Cuna Ekmekcioglu, Peter Willett</authors>
        <title>Effectiveness of stemming for Turkish text retrieval</title>
        <year>2000</year>
        <journal>PROGRAM-ELECTRONIC LIBRARY AND INFORMATION SYSTEMS</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Cuna Ekmekcioglu, Michael Lynch, Peter Willett</authors>
        <title>Stemming and N-gram matching for term conflation in Turkish texts</title>
        <year>1996</year>
        <journal>Information Research</journal>
        <number>2</number>
        <volume>2</volume>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Duzgun, A. P., Gulgez, B., Ozmutlu, A., Ertorul, D., Bugdayci, G., Akyurek, N., Coskun, F.</authors>
        <title>The relationship between intestinal hypoperfusion and serum d-lactate levels during experimental
            intra-abdominal hypertension
        </title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <page>2400-3</page>
        <journal>Dig Dis Sci</journal>
        <number>12</number>
        <volume>51</volume>
        <abstract>Intra-abdominal hypertension (IAH) and abdominal compartment syndrome (ACS) may result from several
            clinic situations and carries high morbidity and mortality risk, particularly in intensive care unit
            patients. The clinical spectrum changes from splanchnic hypoperfusion and intestinal ischemia to multiple
            organ failure. Previous studies demonstrated that serum D-lactate levels may be an early indicator in
            intestinal ischemia. This study aimed to investigate the relationship between intestinal ischemia and serum
            D-lactate levels during experimental IAH. Thirty-two male Wistar Albino rats weighing 250+/-50 g were
            divided into four groups. Three different intra-abdominal pressure (IAP) levels supplied by placement of an
            intraperitoneal Peritofix catheter and iso-osmotic polyethylene glycol infusion. Each of the IAP levels (15,
            20, and 25 mm Hg groups) was checked with the monitor system and fixed for an hour. Control-group animals
            were not subjected to increased IAP. One hour later, 5-ml blood samples were taken for measurement of serum
            D-lactate levels and 2-cm intestinal tissue samples were taken 5 cm proximal to the ileocecal valve for
            histopathologic examination. Elevated serum D-lactate levels were recorded in animals with higher IAP
            levels.There was a positive correlation between serum D-lactate levels and IAP levels. Histological
            examinations of the intestinal tissue samples showed no significant pathologic changes in concordance with
            intestinal ischemia. Serum D-lactate levels may be an early indicator for increased IAP pressure before
            intestinal ischemic changes occur.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Gurkan Dogan</authors>
        <title>Bir Edimbilim Kurami Olarak Baginti</title>
        <year>1990</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Taner Dincer, Bahar Karaoglan, Tarik Kisla</authors>
        <title>A Suffix Based Part-of-Speech Tagger for Turkish</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <journal>Fifth International Conference on Information Technology: New Generation</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Deng-Yiv, Chiu, Ya-Chen, Pan, Wen-Chih, Chang</authors>
        <title>Using rough set theory to construct e-learning faq retrieval infrastructure</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <page>547-552</page>
        <journal>Ubi-Media Computing, 2008 First IEEE International Conference on</journal>
        <abstract>We propose a framework of e-learning FAQ (frequently asked questions) retrieval system by applying
            hierarchical agglomerative clustering method and rough set theory. We try to provide a possible solution to
            improve the learning performance of e-Learning system. The clustering method and FAQ collection are used to
            construct a FAQ clustering concept hierarchy. Then, we use lower/upper approximations in rough set theory to
            classify userspsila queries. The rough set theory can help solve uncertain problem well. Finally, the
            relevant FAQs for the user query are generated. The relevant FAQs are those in the cluster to which the user
            query is assigned.
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>David, Camacho, Maria Dolores, R. Moreno</authors>
        <title>DynJAQ: An adaptive and flexible dynamic FAQ system: Research Articles</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>303-318</page>
        <journal>Int. J. Intell. Syst.</journal>
        <number>3</number>
        <volume>22</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Gokhan Dalkilic, Yalcin Cebi</authors>
        <title>Word Statistics of Turkish Language on a Large Scale Text Corpus -TurCo</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>319-325</page>
        <journal>IEEE International Conference on Information Technology ( ITCC 2004 )</journal>
        <volume>2</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ali Ciltik, Tunga Gungor</authors>
        <title>Time-Efficient Spam E-mail Filtering Using N-gram Models</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <page>19-33</page>
        <journal>Pattern Recognition Letters</journal>
        <number>1</number>
        <volume>29</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Evren Kapusuz Cilden</authors>
        <title>Stemming Turkish Words Using Snowball</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ilyas Cicekli</authors>
        <title>Türkçe ve K ?r?m Tatarcas? Aras?nda Bir Çeviri Sistemi</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <page>123-132</page>
        <journal>Bilgisayar Destekli Dil Bilimi Çal ??tay? Bildirileri</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Chung-Hsien, Wu, Jui-Feng, Yeh, Yu-Sheng, Lai</authors>
        <title>Semantic Segment Extraction and Matching for Internet FAQ Retrieval</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <page>930-940</page>
        <journal>IEEE Transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering</journal>
        <number>7</number>
        <volume>18</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ozlem Cetinoglu, Kemal Oflazer</authors>
        <title>Altsözcüksel Birimlerle Türkçe için Sözcüksel ??levsel Gramer Geli?tirilmesi</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <journal>Fifteenth Turkish Symposium on Artificial Intelligence and Neural Networks (TAINN 2006), 2006</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Fazli Can, Esen Ozkarahan</authors>
        <title>Concepts and effectiveness of the cover coefficient-based clustering methodology for text databases
        </title>
        <year>1990</year>
        <page>483-517</page>
        <journal>ACM Transactions on Database Systems</journal>
        <number>4</number>
        <volume>15</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Fazl? Can, Rabia Nuray, Ayisigi Basak Sevdik</authors>
        <title>Automatic performance evaluation of Web search engines</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>495?514</page>
        <journal>Information Processing and Management</journal>
        <number>3</number>
        <volume>40</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Fazli Can, Seyit Kocberber, Erman Balcik, Cihan Kaynak, Huseyin Cagdas Ocalan, Onur Murat Vursavas
        </authors>
        <title>First large-scale information retrieval experiments on turkish texts</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <journal>ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Fazli Can, Seyit Kocberber, Ozgur Baglioglu, Suleyman Kardas, Huseyin Cagdas Ocalan, Erkan Uyar
        </authors>
        <title>Türkçe Haberlerde Yeni Olay Bulma ve ?zleme: Bir Deney Derleminin Olu?turulmas?</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <journal>De ?i?en Dünyada Bilgi Yönetimi Sempozyumu</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Fazli Can, Ismail Sengor Altingovde, Engin Demir</authors>
        <title>Efficiency and effectiveness of query processing in clusterbased retrieval</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>Information Systems</journal>
        <number>8</number>
        <volume>29</volume>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Berkant Barla Cambazoglu, Cevdet Aykanat</authors>
        <title>Performance of query processing implementations in ranking-based text retrieval systems using inverted
            indices
        </title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <page>875-898</page>
        <journal>Information Processing and Management</journal>
        <number>4</number>
        <volume>42</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Robin Burke, Kristian Hammond, Vladimir Kulyukin, Steven Lytinen, Noriko Tomuro, Scott Schoenberg
        </authors>
        <title>Natural language processing in the faq finder system: Results and prospects</title>
        <year>1997</year>
        <page>26</page>
        <journal>In Working Notes, AAAI spring symposium on NLP on the WWW , Menlo Park, CA</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Christiane Bulut</authors>
        <title>Strategies of Relativization in an Ottoman Turkish Text</title>
        <year>1997</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Cem Bozsahin</authors>
        <title>Turkish Syntax</title>
        <year>1994</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Orhan Bilgin, Ozlem Cetinoglu, Kemal Oflazer</authors>
        <title>Morphosemantic Relations in and Across Wordnets: A Preliminary Study Based on Turkish</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>in Proceedings of the Global WordNet Conference, Brno, Czech Republic</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Orhan Bilgin, Ozlem Cetinoglu, Kemal Oflazer</authors>
        <title>Building a Wordnet for Turkish</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>163-172</page>
        <journal>Romanian Journal of Information Science and Technology Volume 7, Numbers 1-2, 2004</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Armin Bassarak</authors>
        <title>On The Position of the Qestion Marker in Turkish</title>
        <year>1996</year>
        <journal>8th ICTL, Ankara</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>I. Ahmet Aydemir</authors>
        <title>Altay Tuvacasinda gerundiurn c um lelerinin ozne referansina gore tipolojik bir analizi</title>
        <year>1996</year>
        <journal>The 8th International Conference on Turkish Linguistics</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Nart Bedin Atalay, Kemal Oflazer, Bilge Say</authors>
        <title>The Annotation in The Turkish Treebank</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the EACL Workshop on Linguistically Interpreted Corpora - LINC, April 13-14, Budapest,
            Hungary, 2003.
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Alex Andrew, Joyce Andrew, Saban Eren</authors>
        <title>Using Logo to Learn Turkish</title>
        <year>1984</year>
        <journal>The British Computer Society Incorporated by Royal Charter</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Amasyali, M. F.</authors>
        <title>Automatic construction of Turkish wordnet</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <page>248-251</page>
        <journal>Signal Processing and Communications Applications Conference, 2005. Proceedings of the IEEE 13th
        </journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Levent Altunyurt, Zihni Orhan, Tunga Gungor</authors>
        <title>Towards Combining Rule-Based and Statistical Part of Speech Tagging in Agglutinative Languages</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>66-69</page>
        <journal>Computer Engineering</journal>
        <number>1</number>
        <volume>1</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Levent Altunyurt, Zeynep Orhan, Tunga Gungor</authors>
        <title>A Composite Approach for Part of Speech Tagging in Turkish</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <page>19-24</page>
        <journal>Third International Bulgarian-Turkish Conference on Computer Science , ?stanbul</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Levent Altunyurt, Zihni Orhan</authors>
        <title>Part of Speech Tagger for Turkish</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <journal>Department of Computer Engineering</journal>
        <volume>in partial f?lfilment of the requirements for the degree of Bachelor of Science in Computer
            Engineering
        </volume>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ismail Sengor Alt?ngovde, Rifat Ozcan, Huseyin Cagdas Ocalan, Fazli Can, Ozgur Ulusoy</authors>
        <title>Large-scale cluster-based retrieval experiments on Turkish texts</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <journal>ACM SIGIR conference on Research and development in information retrieval</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ahmet Afsin Akin, Mehmet Dundar Akin</authors>
        <title>Zemberek, an open source NLP framework for Turkic Languages</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Judith Aissen, Jorge Flankaner</authors>
        <title>Lexical Extension and Grammatical Transformations</title>
        <year>1980</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Zobel, J., Moffat, A.</authors>
        <title>Inverted files for text search engines</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <page>-</page>
        <journal>Acm Computing Surveys</journal>
        <number>2</number>
        <volume>38</volume>
        <abstract>The technology underlying text search engines has advanced dramatically in the past decade. The
            development of a family of new index representations has led to a wide range of innovations in index
            storage, index construction, and query evaluation. While some of these developments have been consolidated
            in textbooks, many specific techniques are not widely known or the textbook descriptions are out of date. In
            this tutorial, we introduce the key techniques in the area, describing both a core implementation and how
            the core can be enhanced through a range of extensions. We conclude with a comprehensive bibliography of
            text indexing literature.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Deniz Zeyrek</authors>
        <title>Bilimsel Dilbilim, Dil Ulamlari ve Turkçe Eylemlerin Kavramsal Yapisi ile Ilgili Gozlemler</title>
        <year>1998</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Xuan, W. J., Watson, S. J., Meng, F.</authors>
        <title>Tagging sentence boundaries in biomedical literature</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>186-195 648</page>
        <journal>Computational Linguistics and Intelligent Text Processing</journal>
        <volume>4394</volume>
        <abstract>Identifying sentence boundaries is an indispensable task for most natural language processing (NLP)
            systems. While extensive efforts have been devoted to mine biomedical text using NLP techniques, few
            attempts are specifically targeted at disambiguating sentence boundaries in biomedical literature, which has
            a number of unique features that can reduce the accuracy of algorithms designed for general English genre
            significantly. In order to increase the accuracy of sentence boundary identification for biomedical
            literature, we developed a method using a combination of heuristic and statistical strategies. Our approach
            does not require part-of-speech taggers or training procedures. Experiments with biomedical test corpora
            show our system significantly outperforms existing sentence boundary determination algorithms, particularly
            for full text biomedical literature. Our system is very fast and it should also be easily adaptable for
            sentence boundary determination in scientific literature from non-biomedical fields.
        </abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Woods, M. J.</authors>
        <title>Spanish word frequency: A historical surprise</title>
        <year>2001</year>
        <page>231-236</page>
        <journal>Computers and the Humanities</journal>
        <number>2</number>
        <volume>35</volume>
        <abstract>This article compares the word frequencies of the few most common words in Spanish as revealed by a
            modern corpus of over five thousand words with a corpus of Golden-Age Spanish texts of over a million words,
            and finds that although de is by far the most common word in contemporary Spanish, in the 16(th) and 17(th)
            Centuries it was considerably less frequent, and in many texts was less frequent than y, or que for which
            shared very similar frequency figures. It is argued that this significant change in the Spanish language
            comes about in the 20(th) Century.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Vroomen, J., vanZon, M., deGelder, B.</authors>
        <title>Cues to speech segmentation: Evidence from juncture misperceptions and word spotting</title>
        <year>1996</year>
        <page>744-755</page>
        <journal>Memory &amp; Cognition</journal>
        <number>6</number>
        <volume>24</volume>
        <abstract>The question of whether Dutch listeners rely on the rhythmic characteristics of their native language
            to segment speech was investigated in three experiments. In Experiment 1, listeners were induced to make
            missegmentations of continuous speech. The results showed that word boundaries were inserted before strong
            syllables and deleted before weak syllables. In Experiment 2, listeners were required to spot real CVC or
            CVCC words (C = consonant, V = vowel) embedded in bisyllabic nonsense strings. For CVCC words, fewer errors
            were made when the second syllable of the nonsense string was weak rather than strong, whereas for CVC words
            the effect was reversed. Experiment 3 ruled out an acoustic explanation for this effect. It is argued that
            these results are in line with an account in which both metrical segmentation and lexical competition play a
            role.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Umit Deniz Turan</authors>
        <title>Zero Object Arguments and Referentiality in Turkish</title>
        <year>1994</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Dilek Zeynep Hakkani Tur</authors>
        <title>Statistical Language Modeling for Agglutinative Languages</title>
        <year>2000</year>
        <journal>Department of Computer Engineering</journal>
        <volume>Ph.D. Thesis</volume>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Stamatatos, E.</authors>
        <title>A Survey of Modern Authorship Attribution Methods</title>
        <year>2009</year>
        <page>538-556</page>
        <journal>Journal of the American Society for Information Science and Technology</journal>
        <number>3</number>
        <volume>60</volume>
        <abstract>Authorship attribution supported by statistical or computational methods has a long history starting
            from the 19th century and is marked by the seminal study of Mosteller and Wallace (1964) on the authorship
            of the disputed Federalist Papers. During the last decade, this scientific field has been developed
            substantially, taking advantage of research advances in areas such as machine learning, information
            retrieval, and natural language processing. The plethora of available electronic texts (e.g., e-mail
            messages, online forum messages, blogs, source code, etc.) indicates a wide variety of applications of this
            technology, provided it is able to handle short and noisy text from multiple candidate authors. In this
            article, a survey of recent advances of the automated approaches to attributing authorship is presented,
            examining their characteristics for both text representation and text classification. The focus of this
            survey is on computational requirements and settings rather than on linguistic or literary issues. We also
            discuss evaluation methodologies and criteria for authorship attribution studies and list open questions
            that will attract future work in this area.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Spitz, A. L.</authors>
        <title>Determination of the script and language content of document images</title>
        <year>1997</year>
        <page>235-245</page>
        <journal>Ieee Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence</journal>
        <number>3</number>
        <volume>19</volume>
        <abstract>Most document recognition work to date has been performed on English text. Because of the large
            overlap of the character sets found in English and major Western European languages such as French and
            German, some extensions of the basic English capability to those languages have taken place. However,
            automatic language identification prior to optical character recognition is not commonly available and adds
            utility to such systems. Languages and their scripts have attributes that make it possible to determine the
            language of a document automatically. Detection of the values of these attributes requires the recognition
            of particular features of the document image and, in the case of languages using Latin-based symbols, the
            character syntax of the underlying language. We have developed techniques for distinguishing which language
            is represented in an image of text. This work is restricted to a small but important subset of the world's
            languages. The method first classifies the script into two broad classes: Han-based and Latin-based. This
            classification is based on the spatial relationships of features related to the upward concavities in
            character structures. Language identification within the Han script class (Chinese, Japanese, Korean) is
            performed by analysis of the distribution of optical density in the text images. We handle 23 Latin-based
            languages using a technique based on character shape codes, a representation of Latin text that is
            inexpensive to compute.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Spink, Amanda, Ozmutlu, H. Cenk, Aversa, Elizabeth, Manley, Cynthia</authors>
        <title>What do people ask for on the Web and how do they ask it: Ask Jeeves query analysis</title>
        <year>2001</year>
        <page>545-554</page>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 64th Annual Meeting of the American Society for Information Science and Technology
        </journal>
        <abstract>Web search engine users normally enter a series of short Boolean queries. Some Web search services
            such as Ask Jeeves request users to enter queries in the form of questions. Reports findings from a study
            conducted to examine the nature of queries submitted to Ask Jeeves, a publicly accessible question and
            answer (Q&amp;A) search engine. Analyzes about 30,000 queries from a dataset of 800,000 queries. Results
            include: (1) many queries are not in question format; (2) four types of user queries: keyword, Boolean,
            question, and request; (3) common formats for question and request queries. Concludes that these findings
            provide an initial mapping of the structure and content of queries made of Q&amp;A systems. Proceeding
            Published by Information Today, Inc., 2001
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Spink, Amanda, Ozmutlu, H., Aversa, Elizabeth, Manley, Cynthia</authors>
        <title>Sexually related information seeking on the Web</title>
        <year>2001</year>
        <page>382-390</page>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 64th Annual Meeting of the American Society for Information Science and Technology
        </journal>
        <abstract>Queries are the primary means of translating a Web user's information needs in a way that Web systems
            can process. Web queries are as varied as the range of human interest areas, including sexual information
            seeking. A portion of Web queries is sexually related. Reports results of a study of sexually-related
            queries, aiming to provide insight into human sexual information-seeking behavior for use by Web system
            developers. Extracts 116,050 sexually-related queries from a query log of 1,025,910 Excite user queries.
            Finds that many aspects of sexual and non-sexually-related queries exhibit significant differences in terms
            of duration of the session, analysis of the results of each query, and search term usage. Discusses the
            implications of the findings. Proceeding Published by Information Today, Inc., 2001
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Aysin Solak, Kemal Oflazer</authors>
        <title>Parsing Agglutinative Word Structures Its Applications Spelling Checking Turkish</title>
        <year>1992</year>
        <journal>In Proceedings of the 15 th International Conference on Computational Linguistics</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Aysin Solak, Fazli Can</authors>
        <title>Effects of stemming on Turkish text retrieval</title>
        <year>1994</year>
        <page>49-56</page>
        <journal>In Proceedings of the Ninth International. Symposium on Computer and Information Sciences (ISCIS).
            (Antalya,Turkey, November 1994)
        </journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Dan I. Slobin</authors>
        <title>Aphasia in Turkish</title>
        <year>1990</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Engin Sezer</authors>
        <title>Alternation in Turkish</title>
        <year>1981</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Rudman, J.</authors>
        <title>The state of authorship attribution studies: Some problems and solutions</title>
        <year>1997</year>
        <page>351-365</page>
        <journal>Computers and the Humanities</journal>
        <number>4</number>
        <volume>31</volume>
        <abstract>The statement, Results of most non-traditional authorship attribution. studies are not universally
            accepted as definitive, is explicated. A variety of problems in these studies are listed and discussed:
            studies governed by expediency; a lack of competent research; flawed statistical techniques; corrupted
            primary data; lack of expertise in allied fields; a dilettantish approach; inadequate treatment of errors.
            Various solutions are suggested: construct a correct and complete experimental design; educate the
            practitioners; study style in its totality; identify and educate the gatekeepers; develop a complete
            theoretical framework; form an association of practitioners.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Rath, T. M., Manmatha, R.</authors>
        <title>Features for word spotting in historical manuscripts</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <page>218-222 1279</page>
        <journal>Seventh International Conference on Document Analysis and Recognition, Vols I and Ii, Proceedings
        </journal>
        <abstract>For the transition from traditional to digital libraries, the large number of handwritten manuscripts
            that exist pose a great challenge. Easy access to such collections requires an index, which is currently
            created manually at great cost. Because automatic handwriting recognizers fail on historical manuscripts,
            the word spotting technique has been developed: the words in a collection are matched as images and grouped
            into clusters which contain all instances of the same word. By annotating interesting clusters, an index
            that links words to the locations where they occur can be built automatically. Due to the noise in
            historical documents, selecting the right features for matching words is crucial. We analyzed a range of
            features suitable for matching words using dynamic time warping (DTW), which aligns and compares sets of
            features extracted from two images. Each feature's individual performance was measured on a test set. With
            arc average precision of 72%, a combination of features outperforms competing techniques in speed and
            precision.
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Rath, T. M., Manmatha, R.</authors>
        <title>Word image matching using dynamic time warping</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <page>521-527 742</page>
        <journal>2003 Ieee Computer Society Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, Vol Ii, Proceedings
        </journal>
        <abstract>Libraries and other institutions are interested in providing access to scanned versions of their large
            collections of handwritten historical manuscripts on electronic media. Convenient access to a collection
            requires an index, which is manually created at great labour and expense. Since current handwriting
            recognizers do not perform well on historical documents, a technique called word spotting has been
            developed: clusters with occurrences of the same word in a collection are established using image matching.
            By annotating interesting clusters, an index can be built automatically. We present an algorithm for
            matching handwritten words in noisy historical documents. The segmented word images are preprocessed to
            create sets of 1-dimensional features, which are then compared using dynamic time warping. We present
            experimental results on two different data sets from the George Washington collection. Our experiments show
            that this algorithm performs better and is faster than competing matching techniques.
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Raitt, D.</authors>
        <title>Introduction to Modern Information-Retrieval - Salton,G, Mcgill,Mj</title>
        <year>1983</year>
        <page>293-294</page>
        <journal>Online Review</journal>
        <number>4</number>
        <volume>7</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ozmutlu, H. Cenk, Spink, Amanda, Ozmutlu, Seda</authors>
        <title>Analysis of large data logs: an application of Poisson sampling on excite web queries</title>
        <year>2002</year>
        <page>473</page>
        <journal>Information Processing &amp; Management</journal>
        <number>4</number>
        <volume>38</volume>
        <abstract>Presents a study that developed an effective strategy for the selection of samples from large-scale
            data sets used in Web search engines. Definition of search engines; Results from a study using data logs
            from the Excite Web search engine; Use of Poisson sampling in continuous monitoring of stochastic processes;
            Comparison of systematic sampling and Poisson sampling.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>L Ozgur, Tunga Gungor, F Gurgen</authors>
        <title>Spam Mail Detection Using Artificial Neural Network and Bayesian Filter</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>505-510</page>
        <journal>LNCS (Lecture Notes in Computer Science), Springer-Verlag, Berlin Heidelberg</journal>
        <volume>3177</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>A Ozgur, Tunga Gungor</authors>
        <title>Classification of Skewed and Homogeneous Document Corpora with Class-Based and Corpus-Based Keywords
        </title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <journal>29th German Conference on Artificial Intelligence (KI 2006), Eds. C.Freksa, M.Kohlhase and K.Schill,
            June 2006, Bremen
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>ONeill, J. C., Hero, A. O., Williams, W. J.</authors>
        <title>Word spotting via spatial point processes</title>
        <year>1996</year>
        <page>217-220 1067</page>
        <journal>International Conference on Image Processing, Proceedings - Vol Ii</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Kemal Oflazer, Elvan Gocmen, Cem Bozsahin</authors>
        <title>An Outline of Turkish Morphology</title>
        <year>1994</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Rabia Nuray</authors>
        <title>Automatic P erformance E valuation of I nformation R etrieval S ystems</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <journal>Computer Engineering Department</journal>
        <volume>Master Thesis</volume>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Nicolas, S., Kessentini, Y., Paquet, T., Heutte, L.</authors>
        <title>Handwritten document segmentation using hidden Markov random fields</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <page>212-216 1290</page>
        <journal>Eighth International Conference on Document Analysis and Recognition, Vols 1 and 2, Proceedings
        </journal>
        <abstract>In this paper we present a method based on Hidden Markov Random Fields and 2D dynamic programming
            image decoding, for segmenting pages of complex handwritten manuscripts such as novelist drafts. After a
            formal description of the theoretical framework and the principles of the decoding method, we describe the
            implementation of the model and the decoding method. Then we discuss the results obtained with this approach
            on the drafts of the French novelist Gustave Flaubert.
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Monz, C., de Rijke, M.</authors>
        <title>Shallow morphological analysis in monolingual information retrieval for Dutch, German, and Italian
        </title>
        <year>2002</year>
        <page>262-277</page>
        <journal>Evlauation of Cross-Language Information Retrieval Systems</journal>
        <volume>2406</volume>
        <abstract>This paper describes the experiments of our team for CLEF 2001, which include both official and
            post-submission runs. We took part in the monolingual task for Dutch, German, and Italian. The focus of our
            experiments was on the effects of morphological analyses, such as stemming and compound splitting, on
            retrieval effectiveness. Confirming earlier reports on retrieval in compound splitting languages such as
            Dutch and German, we found improvements to be around 25% for German and as much as 69% for Dutch. For
            Italian, lexicon-based stemming resulted in gains of up to 25%.
        </abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Mikheev, A.</authors>
        <title>Tagging sentence boundaries</title>
        <year>2000</year>
        <page>A264-A271 717</page>
        <journal>6th Applied Natural Language Processing Conference/1st Meeting of the North American Chapter of the
            Association for Computational Linguistics, Proceedings of the Conference and Proceedings of the Anlp-Naacl
            2000 Student Research Workshop
        </journal>
        <abstract>In this paper we tackle sentence boundary disambiguation through a part-of-speech (POS) tagging
            framework. We describe necessary changes in text tokenization and the implementation of a POS tagger and
            provide results of an evaluation of this System on two corpora. We also describe an extension of the
            traditional POS tagging by combining it with the document-centered approach to proper name identification
            and abbreviation handling. This made the resulting system robust to domain and topic shifts.
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Robert H. Meskill</authors>
        <title>A Transformational Analysis of Turkish Syntax</title>
        <year>1970</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Manmatha, R., Rothfeder, J. L.</authors>
        <title>A scale space approach for automatically segmenting words from historical handwritten documents</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <page>1212-1225</page>
        <journal>Ieee Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence</journal>
        <number>8</number>
        <volume>27</volume>
        <abstract>Many libraries, museums, and other organizations contain large collections of handwritten historical
            documents, for example, the papers of early presidents like George Washington at the Library of Congress.
            The first step in providing recognition/retrieval tools is to automatically segment handwritten pages into
            words. State of the art segmentation techniques like the gap metrics algorithm have been mostly developed
            and tested on highly constrained documents like bank checks and postal addresses. There has been little work
            on full handwritten pages and this work has usually involved testing on clean artificial documents created
            for the purpose of research. Historical manuscript images, on the other hand, contain a great deal of noise
            and are much more challenging. Here, a novel scale space algorithm for automatically segmenting handwritten
            ( historical) documents into words is described. First, the page is cleaned to remove margins. This is
            followed by a gray-level projection profile algorithm for finding lines in images. Each line image is then
            filtered with an anisotropic Laplacian at several scales. This procedure produces blobs which correspond to
            portions of characters at small scales and to words at larger scales. Crucial to the algorithm is scale
            selection, that is, finding the optimum scale at which blobs correspond to words. This is done by finding
            the maximum over scale of the extent or area of the blobs. This scale maximum is estimated using three
            different approaches. The blobs recovered at the optimum scale are then bounded with a rectangular box to
            recover the words. A postprocessing filtering step is performed to eliminate boxes of unusual size which are
            unlikely to correspond to words. The approach is tested on a number of different data sets and it is shown
            that, on 100 sampled documents from the George Washington corpus of handwritten document images, a total
            error rate of 17 percent is observed. The technique outperforms a state-of-the-art gap metrics
            word-segmentation algorithm on this collection.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Manmatha, R., Han, C. F., Riseman, E. M.</authors>
        <title>Word spotting: A new approach to indexing handwriting</title>
        <year>1996</year>
        <page>631-637 932</page>
        <journal>1996 Ieee Computer Society Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition, Proceedings</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Li, Y. J., Chung, S. M., Holt, J. D.</authors>
        <title>Text document clustering based on frequent word meaning sequences</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <page>381-404</page>
        <journal>Data &amp; Knowledge Engineering</journal>
        <number>1</number>
        <volume>64</volume>
        <abstract>Most of existing text clustering algorithms use the vector space model, which treats documents as bags
            of words. Thus, word sequences in the documents are ignored, while the meaning of natural languages strongly
            depends on them. In this paper, we propose two new text clustering algorithms, named Clustering based on
            Frequent Word Sequences (CFWS) and Clustering based on Frequent Word Meaning Sequences (CFWMS). A word is
            the word form showing in the document, and a word meaning is the concept expressed by synonymous word forms.
            A word (meaning) sequence is frequent if it occurs in more than certain percentage of the documents in the
            text database. The frequent word (meaning) sequences can provide compact and valuable information about
            those text documents. For experiments, we used the Reuters-21578 text collection, CISI documents of the
            Classic data set [Classic data set, ftp://ftp.cs.cornell.edu/pub/smart/], and a corpus of the Text Retrieval
            Conference (TREC) [High Accuracy Retrieval from Documents (HARD) Track of Text Retrieval Conference, 2004].
            Our experimental results show that CFWS and CFWMS have much better clustering accuracy than Bisecting
            k-means (BKM) [M. Steinbach, G. Karypis, V. Kumar, A Comparison of Document Clustering Techniques, KDD-2000
            Workshop on Text Mining, 2000], a modified bisecting k-means using background knowledge (BBK) [A. Hotho, S.
            Staab, G. Stumme, Ontologies improve text document clustering, in: Proceedings of the 3rd IEEE International
            Conference on Data Mining, 2003, pp. 541-544] and Frequent Itemset-based Hierarchical Clustering (FIHC)
            [B.C.M. Fung, K. Wang, M. Ester, Hierarchical document clustering using frequent itemsets, in: Proceedings
            of SIAM International Conference on Data Mining, 2003] algorithms. (c) 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights
            reserved.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Lewis, D. D., Sparck-Jones, K.</authors>
        <title>Natural language processing for information retrieval</title>
        <year>1996</year>
        <page>92-101</page>
        <journal>Communications of the Acm</journal>
        <number>1</number>
        <volume>39</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Lewis, D. D.</authors>
        <title>An Evaluation of Phrasal and Clustered Representations on a Text Categorization Task</title>
        <year>1992</year>
        <page>37-50 353</page>
        <journal>Sigir 92 : Proceedings of the Fifteenth Annual International Acm Sigir Conference on Research and
            Development in Information Retrieval
        </journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Levinger, M., Itai, T., Ornan, U.</authors>
        <title>Learning Morpho-Lexical Probabilities from an Untagged Corpus with an Application to Hebrew</title>
        <year>1995</year>
        <page>383-404</page>
        <journal>Computational Linguistics</journal>
        <number>3</number>
        <volume>21</volume>
        <abstract>This paper proposes a new approach for acquiring morpho-lexical probabilities from an untagged corpus.
            This approach demonstrates a way to extract very useful and nontrivial information from an untagged corpus,
            which otherwise would require laborious tagging of large corpora. The paper describes the use of these
            morpho-lexical probabilities as an information source for morphological disambiguation in Hebrew. The
            suggested method depends primarily on the following property: a lexical entry in Hebrew may have many
            different word forms, some of which are ambiguous and some of which are nor. Thus, the disambiguation of a
            given word can be achieved using other word forms of the same lexical entry. Even though it was originally
            devised and implemented for dealing with the morphological ambiguity problem in Hebrew, the basic idea can
            be extended and used to handle similar problems in other languages with rich morphology.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Robert B. Lees</authors>
        <title>The phonology of Modern Standard Turkish</title>
        <year>1961</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>S Kuru, Tunga Gungor</authors>
        <title>Towards a Two Level Grammar for the Turkish Noun Phrase</title>
        <year>1993</year>
        <journal>International Second Turkish Symposium on Artificial Intelligence and Artificial Neural Networks (TAINN
            1993) , Istanbul
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>S Kuru, Tunga Güngör</authors>
        <title>Knowledge Transformation: Generating Causal Relations from Mathematical Models</title>
        <year>1989</year>
        <journal>Fourth International Symposium on Computer and Information Sciences (ISCIS 1989), Izmir</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Kural, Y., Robertson, S., Jones, S.</authors>
        <title>Deciphering cluster representations</title>
        <year>2001</year>
        <page>593-601</page>
        <journal>Information Processing &amp; Management</journal>
        <number>4</number>
        <volume>37</volume>
        <abstract>There are several recent studies that propose search output clustering as an alternative
            representation method to ranked output. Users are provided with cluster representations instead of lists of
            titles and invited to make decisions on groups of documents. This paper discusses the difficulties involved
            in representing clusters for users' evaluation in a concise but easily interpretable form. The discussion is
            based on findings and user feedback from a user study investigating the effectiveness of search output
            clustering. The overall impression created by the experiment results and users' feedback is that clusters
            cannot be relied on to consistently produce meaningful document groups that can easily be recognised by the
            users. They also seem to lead to unrealistic user expectations. (C) 2001 Elsevier Science Ltd. All rights
            reserved.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Murat Kural</authors>
        <title>Postverbal Constituents in Turkish and the Linear Correspondence Axiom</title>
        <year>1997</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Murat Kural</authors>
        <title>Properties of scrambling in Turkish</title>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <year>Unknown</year>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Krovetz, R. T.</authors>
        <title>Viewing morphology as an inference process</title>
        <year>2000</year>
        <page>277-294</page>
        <journal>Artificial Intelligence</journal>
        <number>1-2</number>
        <volume>118</volume>
        <abstract>Morphology is the area of linguistics concerned with the internal structure of words. Information
            retrieval has generally not paid much attention to word structure, other than to account for some of the
            variability in word forms via the use of stemmers. We report on our experiments to determine the importance
            of morphology, and the effect that it has on performance. We found that grouping morphological variants
            makes a significant improvement in retrieval performance. Improvements are seen by grouping inflectional as
            well as derivational variants. We also found that performance was enhanced by recognizing lexical phrases.
            We describe the interaction between morphology and lexical ambiguity, and how resolving that ambiguity will
            lead to further improvements in performance. (C) 2000 Published by Elsevier Science B.V. All rights
            reserved.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Kotaro, Takahiro HARA, Shojiro NISHIO</authors>
        <title>A Thesaurus Construction Method from Large ScaleWeb Dictionaries</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <journal>Proceedings of the 21st International Conference on Advanced Networking and Applications</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Jaklin Kornfilt</authors>
        <title>Directionality of Identical Verb Deletion in Turkish Coordination</title>
        <year>2000</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Aydin Koksal</authors>
        <title>Tümüyle Ö zdevimli D eneysel B ir B elge D izinleme ve E ri ?im D izgesi: TÜRDER</title>
        <year>1981</year>
        <page>37-44</page>
        <journal>In the Proceedings of 3. Ulusal Bili ?im Kurultay? ( TBD 3. Ulusal Bili?im Kurultay? )</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Knill, K. M., Young, S. J.</authors>
        <title>Fast implementation methods for Viterbi-based word-spotting</title>
        <year>1996</year>
        <page>522-525 3588</page>
        <journal>1996 Ieee International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing, Conference Proceedings,
            Vols 1-6
        </journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Keskin, U., Ataer, O. E.</authors>
        <title>Theoretical Investigation of Production of Spherical Material Powders Via Thermal Plasma</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <page>35-44</page>
        <journal>Isi Bilimi Ve Teknigi Dergisi-Journal of Thermal Science and Technology</journal>
        <number>2</number>
        <volume>28</volume>
        <abstract>Inductively coupled plasma systems are appropriate equipments for the spheroidization processes of
            powder materials because they have large volumes, high purities, and axial powder injection properties.
            Especially the long residence times of powders inside the plasma in the reactor are another advantage of
            ICTPs. The fundamentals of the production of spherical ceramic powders via inductively coupled thermal
            plasma systems include melting process of powders in the plasma jet and free falling of them through the
            reactor. This theoretical study was made as groundwork of the planned study by an inductively coupled
            thermal plasma system. A theoretical study was made on spheroidization of powders via thermal plasma
            systems. In the study, nonlinear momentum and energy equations were numerically solved through a computer
            code written in FORTRAN. The effects of plasma gas temperature and velocity, nozzle and particle diameter,
            initial particle temperature and velocity, and the volume flow rate of plasma gas on particle temperature
            and velocity were investigated in the analysis. The results obtained via the fifth order Runge-Kutta method
            were given as diagrams.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Sarah D. Kennely</authors>
        <title>Theta Government in Turkish Effects On Ip Dominated by DP1</title>
        <year>1994</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Sarah D. Kennelly</authors>
        <title>The Semantics of Clausal Determiners:Subject/Object Asymmetry in Participles</title>
        <year>1994</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Sarah D. Kennelly</authors>
        <title>Caseless Existential DPs in Turkish</title>
        <year>1994</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Sarah D. Kennelly</authors>
        <title>Turkish Subordination: [-Tense, -CP, +Case]</title>
        <year>1992</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Karabulut, H., Ataer, O. E.</authors>
        <title>Numerical solution of boundary layer equations in compressible cross-flow to a cylinder</title>
        <year>1998</year>
        <page>2677-2685</page>
        <journal>International Journal of Heat and Mass Transfer</journal>
        <number>17</number>
        <volume>41</volume>
        <abstract>Two-dimensional, steady-state, compressible boundary layer and energy equations are solved numerically
            using finite difference method in cylindrical coordinates. The heat transfer from and to an isolated
            cylinder for cross-flow is calculated up to the separation point iteratively. The velocity and temperature
            profiles, and local Nusselt numbers around the cylinder are obtained for the constant wall temperature
            boundary condition at different oncoming velocities. The results are obtained for compressible and
            incompressible how and given in diagrams. (C) 1998 Elsevier Science Ltd. All rights reserved.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Masahiro Ito, Kotaro Nakayama, Takahiro Hara, Shojiro Nishio</authors>
        <title>Association thesaurus construction methods based on link co-occurrence analysis for wikipedia</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <journal>Proceeding of the 17th ACM conference on Information and knowledge management</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Hull, D. A.</authors>
        <title>Stemming algorithms: A case study for detailed evaluation</title>
        <year>1996</year>
        <page>70-84</page>
        <journal>Journal of the American Society for Information Science</journal>
        <number>1</number>
        <volume>47</volume>
        <abstract>The majority of information retrieval experiments are evaluated by measures such as average precision
            and average recall. Fundamental decisions about the superiority of one retrieval technique over another are
            made solely on the basis of these measures. We claim that average performance figures need to be validated
            with a careful statistical analysis and that there is a great deal of additional information that can be
            uncovered by looking closely at the results of individual queries. This article is a case study of stemming
            algorithms which describes a number of novel approaches to evaluation and demonstrates their value.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Hochberg, J., Kelly, P., Thomas, T., Kerns, L.</authors>
        <title>Automatic script identification from document images using cluster-based templates</title>
        <year>1997</year>
        <page>176-181</page>
        <journal>Ieee Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence</journal>
        <number>2</number>
        <volume>19</volume>
        <abstract>We describe an automated script identification system for typeset document images. Templates for each
            script are created by clustering textual symbols from a training set. Symbols from new images are compared
            to the templates to find the best script. Our current system processes thirteen scripts with minimal
            preprocessing and high accuracy.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Hartmann, C., Ozmutlu, O., Petermeier, H., Fried, J., Delgado, A.</authors>
        <title>Analysis of the flow field induced by the sessile peritrichous ciliate Opercularia asymmetrica</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>137-48</page>
        <journal>J Biomech</journal>
        <number>1</number>
        <volume>40</volume>
        <abstract>The feeding mechanism of the sessile protozoon Opercularia asymmetrica (Oligohymenophorea,
            Peritrichia) relies on the cilia beat generating a flow field that convectively transports suspended
            particles and dissolved substances to the oral cavity of the organism. By use of optical micro-flow
            measurement and theoretical methods the flow environment of two neighbouring peritrichous ciliate cells is
            studied. Both, yeast cells (Saccharomyces cerevisiae) and artificial flow tracers are used for the
            visualisation of the flow field. Artificial tracers are rejected by the protozoa and deviate from the fluid
            path lines, while yeast cells follow the flow almost perfectly. This is shown through a dimensional analysis
            of the involved hydrodynamic forces on the tracers. The measured flow field exhibits maximum velocities of
            25 microm/s at around 20 microm distance ahead of an individual ciliate. The flow field extends 200 microm
            from the location of the ciliate. A nicking motion of the protozoon is observed and found not to obey any
            periodic law. Multiples of protozoa exhibit most commonly an alternating cilia beat regime generating a
            non-stationary flow field. It can be shown through theoretical methods that fluid exchange is enhanced in
            this alternating regime compared to a flow field generated by a single ciliate. Fluid exchange depends on
            the distance of the ciliates from each other and on the alteration frequency of the cilia beat. The
            comparison of an analytical Stokes' flow solution with the observed fluid flow serves to determine the force
            required to maintain the flow field against viscous dissipation. The force magnitude is in the order of
            magnitude of 10-100 pN.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>O Gungor, Tunga Gungor</authors>
        <title>Türkçe bir Sözlükteki Tan ? mlardan Kavramlar Aras ? ndaki Üst-Kavram ? li ? kilerinin Ç ? kar ? lmas ?
        </title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <journal>Akademik Bili ? im Konferans ?</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Zelal Giingcrdii, Elisabet Engdahlt</authors>
        <title>An HPSG Account of Relativization in Turkish</title>
        <year>1998</year>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ferrari, V., Fevrier, L., Jurie, F., Schmid, C.</authors>
        <title>Groups of adjacent contour segments for object detection</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <page>36-51</page>
        <journal>Ieee Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence</journal>
        <number>1</number>
        <volume>30</volume>
        <abstract>We present a family of scale-invariant local shape features formed by chains of k connected roughly
            straight contour segments (kAS), and their use for object class detection. kAS are able to cleanly encode
            pure fragments of an object boundary without including nearby clutter. Moreover, they offer an attractive
            compromise between information content and repeatability and encompass a wide variety of local shape
            structures. We also define a translation and scale invariant descriptor encoding the geometric configuration
            of the segments within a kAS, making kAS easy to reuse in other frameworks, for example, as a replacement or
            addition to interest points (IPs). Software for detecting and describing kAS is released at
            http://lear.inrialpes.fr/software. We demonstrate the high performance of kAS within a simple but powerful
            sliding-window object detection scheme. Through extensive evaluations, involving eight diverse object
            classes and more than 1,400 images, we 1) study the evolution of performance as the degree of feature
            complexity k varies and determine the best degree, 2) show that kAS substantially outperform IPs for
            detecting shape-based classes, and 3) compare our object detector to the recent state-of-the-art system by
            Dalal and Triggs [4].
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Esterl, S., Ozmutlu, O., Hartmann, C., Delgado, A.</authors>
        <title>Three-dimensional numerical approach to investigate the substrate transport and conversion in an
            immobilized enzyme reactor
        </title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <page>780-9</page>
        <journal>Biotechnol Bioeng</journal>
        <number>7</number>
        <volume>83</volume>
        <abstract>This numerical study evaluates the momentum and mass transfer in an immobilized enzyme reactor. The
            simulation is based on the solution of the three-dimensional Navier-Stokes equation and a scalar transport
            equation with a sink term for the transport and the conversion of substrate to product. The reactor consists
            of a container filled with 20 spherical enzyme carriers. Each of these carriers is covered with an active
            enzyme layer where the conversion takes place. To account for the biochemical activity, the sink term in the
            scalar transport equation is represented by a standard Michaelis-Menten approach. The simulation gives
            detailed information of the local substrate and product concentrations with respect to external and internal
            transport limitations. A major focus is set on the influence of the substrate transport velocity on the
            catalytic process. For reactor performance analysis the overall and the local transport processes are
            described by a complete set of dimensionless variables. The interaction between substrate concentration,
            velocity, and efficiency of the process can be studied with the help of these variables. The effect of
            different substrate inflow concentrations on the process can be seen in relation to velocity variations. The
            flow field characterization of the system makes it possible to understand fluid mechanical properties and
            its importance to transport processes. The distribution of fluid motion through the void volume has
            different properties in different parts of the reactor. This phenomenon has strong effects on the
            arrangement of significantly different mass transport areas as well as on process effectiveness. With the
            given data it is also possible to detect zones of high, low, and latent enzymatic activity and to determine
            whether the conversion is limited due to mass transfer or reaction resistances.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>C una Ekmekcioglu, Michael Lynch, Peter Willett</authors>
        <title>Development and evaluation of conflation techniques for the implementation of a document retrieval system
            for Turkish text databases
        </title>
        <year>1995</year>
        <page>131-146</page>
        <journal>The New Review of Document and Text Management</journal>
        <volume>1</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Cuna Ekmekcioglu, Michael Lynch, Robertson, A.M., Tengku Mohd Sembok, Peter Willett</authors>
        <title>Comparison of n-gram matching and stemming for term conflation in English, Malay, and Turkish texts
        </title>
        <year>1996</year>
        <page>1-14</page>
        <journal>Text Technology</journal>
        <volume>6</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Gokmen Duran, Hayri Sever</authors>
        <title>Türkçe Gövdeleme Algoritmalar ?n?n Analizi</title>
        <year>1996</year>
        <page>235-243</page>
        <journal>In Proceedings of Annual Conference of Turkish Informatic Association</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ding, J., Lam, L., Suen, C. Y.</authors>
        <title>Classification of oriental and European scripts by using characteristic features</title>
        <year>1997</year>
        <page>1023-1027 1112</page>
        <journal>Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Document Analysis and Recognition, Vols 1 and 2
        </journal>
        <abstract>Two types of techniques are usually adopted in language differentiation: token matching and
            statistical analysis. In this paper we present a method which uses a combined analysis of several
            discriminating statistical features, for the differentiation between European and oriental language scripts.
            When applied to more than 23 languages, it has proved to be effective in classifying documents printed in
            these different scripts.
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Bekir Taner Dincer, Bahar Karaoglan</authors>
        <title>Sentence boundary detection in Turkish</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>255-262</page>
        <journal>Advances in Information Systems, Proceedings</journal>
        <volume>3261</volume>
        <abstract>In this paper, we describe a solution method for sentence boundary detection in Turkish. The method
            exploits simple heuristic knowledge of Turkish syllabication and its phonetic rules for disambiguation of
            dots. The test accuracy of the algorithm is measured as 96.02%. The main contribution of this study is
            considered as presenting a new lexicon free method for differentiating EOS (end of sentence) dots from the
            ones that are used for other purposes.
        </abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Bekir Taner Dincer, Bahar Karaoglan</authors>
        <title>The effect of part-of-speech tagging on IR performance for Turkish</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <journal>COMPUTER AND INFORMATION SCIENCES - ISCIS 2004, PROCEEDINGS</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Bekir Taner Dincer, Bahar Karaoglan</authors>
        <title>Stemming in A gglutinative L anguages: A P robabilistic S temmer for Turkish</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <page>244-251</page>
        <journal>Computer and Information Sciences - Iscis 2003</journal>
        <volume>2869</volume>
        <abstract>In this paper, we introduce a new lexicon free, probabilistic stemmer to be used in a developing
            Turkish Information Retrieval system. It has a linear computational complexity and its test success ratio is
            95.8%. The main contribution of this paper is to give a thorough description of a probabilistic perspective
            for stemming which can also be generalized to apply to other agglutinative languages like Finnish,
            Hungarian, Estonian and Czech.
        </abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Dermatas, E., Kokkinakis, G.</authors>
        <title>Automatic Stochastic Tagging of Natural-Language Texts</title>
        <year>1995</year>
        <page>137-163</page>
        <journal>Computational Linguistics</journal>
        <number>2</number>
        <volume>21</volume>
        <abstract>Five language and tagset independent stochastic taggers, handling morphological and contextual
            information, are presented and tested in corpora of seven European languages (Dutch, English, French,
            German, Creek, Italian and Spanish), using two sets of grammatical tags; a small set containing the eleven
            main grammatical classes and a large set of grammatical categories common to all languages. The unknown
            words are tagged using an experimentally proven stochastic hypothesis that links the stochastic behavior of
            the unknown words with that of the less probable known words. A fully automatic training and tagging program
            has been implemented on an IBM PC-compatible 80386-based computer. Measurements of error rate, time
            response, and memory requirements have shown that the taggers' performance is satisfactory, even though a
            small training text is available. The error rate is improved when new texts are used to update the
            stochastic model parameters.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Rabia Gulcin Demirci, Vildan Kismir, Yiltan Bitirim</authors>
        <title>An Evaluation of Popular Search Engines on Finding Turkish Documents</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <journal>ICIW apos;07. Second International Conference</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Mehmet Emin Dalkilic, Gokhan Dalkilic</authors>
        <title>Some Important Statistical Properties of Printed Turkish</title>
        <year>2002</year>
        <page>113-130</page>
        <journal>Journal of Statistical Research,</journal>
        <volume>1-1</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Dalkilic, M. E., Dalkilic, G.</authors>
        <title>On the cryptographic patterns and frequencies in Turkish language</title>
        <year>2002</year>
        <page>144-153</page>
        <journal>Advances in Information Systems</journal>
        <volume>2457</volume>
        <abstract>Although Turkish is a significant language with over 60 million native speakers, its cryptographic
            characteristics are relatively unknown. In this paper, some language patterns and frequencies of Turkish
            (such as letter frequency profile, letter contact patterns, most frequent digrams, trigrams and words,
            common word beginnings and endings, vowel/consonant patterns, etc.) relevant to information security,
            cryptography and plaintext recognition applications are presented and discussed. The data is collected from
            a large Turkish corpus and the usage of the data is illustrated through cryptanalysis of a mono-alphabetic
            substitution cipher. A new vowel identification method is developed using a distinct pattern of
            Turkish-(almost) non-existence of double consonants at word boundaries.
        </abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Gokhan Dalkilic, Yalcin Cebi</authors>
        <title>Zipf's Law and Mandelbrot's C onstants for Turkish L anguage U sing Turkish C orpus (TurCo)</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>273-282</page>
        <journal>ADVIS 2004, LNCS 3261, Springer Verlag</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Gokhan Dalkilic, Yalcin Cebi</authors>
        <title>A 300 MB Turkish corpus and word analysis</title>
        <year>2002</year>
        <page>205-212</page>
        <journal>Advances in Information Systems</journal>
        <volume>2457</volume>
        <abstract>In order to determine some properties of a language, a corpus of that language should be created. To
            analyze Turkish language, at first, a Turkish corpus having similar to300 MB capacity and more than 44
            million words was prepared by using 10 different web sites having Turkish content. Most frequently used word
            statistics of Turkish were calculated by using this corpus. Frequencies of most frequently used first 7
            words were compared with their equivalent in English, and it was found out that most frequently used words
            are not nouns in natural languages Most frequently used words having 1 to 5 letters were determined and they
            were applied onto a randomly selected text in order to test the validity of the process.
        </abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Cussens, J., Dzeroski, S., Erjavec, T.</authors>
        <title>Morphosyntactic tagging of Slovene using Progol</title>
        <year>1999</year>
        <page>68-79</page>
        <journal>Inductive Logic Programming</journal>
        <volume>1634</volume>
        <abstract>We consider the task of tagging Slovene words with morphosyntactic descriptions (MSDs). MSDs contain
            not only part-of-speech information but also attributes such as gender and case. In the case of Slovene
            there are 2,083 possible MSDs. P-Progol was used to learn morphosyntactic disambiguation rules from
            annotated data (consisting of 161,314 examples) produced by the MULTEXT-East project. P-Progol produced
            1,148 rules taking 36 hours. Using simple grammatical background knowledge, e.g. looking for case
            disagreement, P-Progol induced 4,094 clauses in eight parallel runs. These rules have proved effective at
            detecting and explaining incorrect MSD annotations in an independent test set, but have not so far produced
            a tagger comparable to other existing taggers in terms of accuracy.
        </abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>George N. Clements, Engin Sezer</authors>
        <title>Voweland Consonant Disharmony in Turkish</title>
        <year>1982</year>
        <page>213-255</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ozlem Cetinoglu</authors>
        <title>A Prolog Based Natural Language Processing Infrastructure for Turkish</title>
        <year>2001</year>
        <volume>Ms Thesis</volume>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <journal>Unknown</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ebru Celikel, Mehmet Emin Dalkilic, Gokhan Dalkilic</authors>
        <title>Word-Based Fixed and Flexible List Compression</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <page>780-790</page>
        <journal>ISCIS 2005, LNCS 3733, Springer Verlag</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Yalcin Cebi Gokhan Dalkilic</authors>
        <title>Turkish word N-gram analyzing algorithms for a large scale Turkish corpus - TurCo</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>236-240</page>
        <journal>International Conference on Information Technology: Coding Computing, ITCC 2004</journal>
        <volume>2</volume>
        <abstract>To calculate some statistical properties of a language, first you need to take some samples of that
            language. That sample is called a corpus. An unbalanced large scale Turkish text corpus (TurCo) having
            [similar to] 362 MB capacity and more than 50 million words was prepared by using 12 different resources
            including web sites and novels in Turkish language. Different algorithms were tested to obtain the n-gram (1
            [less-than or equal to] n [less-than or equal to] 5) values. Efficiencies of different algorithms have been
            examined by applying them onto the each piece of the corpus one by one. Only detailed results of the two
            algorithms created without using database tables are given, because all the other algorithms need to run
            more than one day which makes those tests inefficient.
        </abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Can, F., Patton, J. M.</authors>
        <title>Change of writing style with time</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>61-82</page>
        <journal>Computers and the Humanities</journal>
        <number>1</number>
        <volume>38</volume>
        <abstract>This study investigates the writing style change of two Turkish authors, Cetin Altan and Yasar Kemal,
            in their old and new works using respectively their newspaper columns and novels. The style markers are the
            frequencies of word lengths in both text and vocabulary, and the rate of usage of most frequent words. For
            both authors, t-tests and logistic regressions show that the length of the words in new works is
            significantly longer than that of the old. The principal component analyses graphically illustrate the
            separation between old and new texts. The works are correctly categorized as old or new with 75 to 100%
            accuracy and 92% average accuracy using discriminant analysis-based cross validation. The results imply
            higher time gap may have positive impact in separation and categorization. For Altan a regression analysis
            demonstrates a decrease in average word length as the age of his column increases. One interesting
            observation is that for one word each author has similar preference changes over time.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Fazli Can</authors>
        <title>Incremental clustering for dynamic information processing</title>
        <year>1993</year>
        <page>143-164</page>
        <journal>ACM Transactions on Information Systems</journal>
        <volume>10</volume>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Camacho, David, Rodriguez-Moreno, Maria Dolores, López, Alberto, Castro, César</authors>
        <title>Using Hierarchical Knowledge Structures to Implement Dynamic FAQ Systems</title>
        <year>2004</year>
        <page>496-507</page>
        <journal>Practical Aspects of Knowledge Management</journal>
        <abstract>This paper presents a knowledge representation that allows building hierarchical structures that can
            be used to build dynamically solutions to solve a particular user question. The goal of this work is to show
            how it is possible to define (and handle) a new knowledge representation that allows the integration of
            Case-based Knowledge into a graph-based representation that can be easily learned and managed. The
            combination of both, Case-based Knowledge and graphs allows to implement a flexible hierarchical structures
            (or learning graphs) that have been applied to implement a new kind of Frequently Asked Questions Systems.
            In these systems the output is dynamically built from the user query, using as basis structures the
            knowledge retrieved from a Case Base. The paper shows how the management of these cases allow enriching the
            knowledge base. Finally, the paper shows a specific application of this technique, in particular a Web
            system named DynJAQ (Dynamic Java Asked Questions). DynJAQ is a FAQ system that is able to generate
            dynamically several HTML guides that can be used to answer any possible question about a particular
            programming language (Java). Keywords: Knowledge Representation, Case-Based Reasoning, Intelligent Web
            Systems.
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Brill, E.</authors>
        <title>Transformation-based error-driven learning and natural language processing: A case study in
            part-of-speech tagging
        </title>
        <year>1995</year>
        <page>543-565</page>
        <journal>Computational Linguistics</journal>
        <number>4</number>
        <volume>21</volume>
        <abstract>Recently, there hits been a rebirth of empiricism in the field of natural language processing. Manual
            encoding of linguistic information is being challenged by automated corpus-based learning as a method of
            providing a natural language processing system with linguistic knowledge. Although corpus-based approaches
            have been successful in many different areas of natural language processing, it is often the case that these
            methods capture the linguistic information they are modelling indirectly in large opaque tables of
            statistics. This can make it difficult to analyze, understand and improve the ability of these approaches to
            model underlying linguistic behavior. In this paper, we will describe a simple rule-based approach to
            automated learning of linguistic knowledge. This approach has been shown for a number of tasks to capture
            information in a clearer and more direct fashion without a compromise in performance. We present a detailed
            case study of this learning method applied to part-of-speech tagging.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Brants, T.</authors>
        <title>TnT - A statistical part-of-speech tagger</title>
        <year>2000</year>
        <page>224-231 717</page>
        <journal>6th Applied Natural Language Processing Conference/1st Meeting of the North American Chapter of the
            Association for Computational Linguistics, Proceedings of the Conference and Proceedings of the Anlp-Naacl
            2000 Student Research Workshop
        </journal>
        <abstract>Trigrams'n'Tags (TnT) is an efficient statistical part-of-speech tagger. Contrary to claims found
            elsewhere in the literature, we argue that a tagger based on Markov models performs at least as well as
            other current approaches, including the Maximum Entropy framework. A recent comparison has even shown that
            TnT performs significantly better for the tested corpora. We describe the basic model of TnT, the techniques
            used for smoothing and for handling unknown words. Furthermore, we present evaluations on two corpora.
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Bilgili, M., Ataer, O. E.</authors>
        <title>Numerical analysis of hydrogen absorption in a P/M metal bed</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <page>141-148</page>
        <journal>Powder Technology</journal>
        <number>2</number>
        <volume>160</volume>
        <abstract>In a porous metal bed, two-dimensional heat and mass transfer are analyzed for hydrogen absorption in
            the cylindrical coordinates. For high cooling rates an annular geometry is selected for the porous metal
            bed, and the bed is cooled by a fluid on both the internal and the external surfaces. The absorption process
            is analyzed numerically for the porous LaNi5 P/M metal bed. Variations of the metal hydride temperature and
            hydrogen/metal atomic ratio are calculated in the radial and axial directions using a computational fluid
            dynamics (CFD) program. It is observed that the hydride formation takes places near the cold boundaries. The
            results are compared with the numerical results given in the literature for different geometries. (c) 2005
            Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Barnard, K., Duygulu, P., Forsyth, D., de Freitas, N., Blei, D. M., Jordan, M. I.</authors>
        <title>Matching words and pictures</title>
        <year>2003</year>
        <page>1107-1135</page>
        <journal>Journal of Machine Learning Research</journal>
        <number>6</number>
        <volume>3</volume>
        <abstract>We present a new approach for modeling multi-modal data sets, focusing on the specific case of
            segmented images with associated text. Learning the joint distribution of image regions and words has many
            applications. We consider in detail predicting words associated with whole images (auto-annotation) and
            corresponding to particular image regions (region naming). Auto-annotation might help organize and access
            large collections of images. Region naming is a model of object recognition as a process of translating
            image regions to words, much as one might translate from one language to another. Learning the relationships
            between image regions and semantic correlates (words) is an interesting example of multi-modal data mining,
            particularly because it is typically hard to apply data mining techniques to collections of images. We
            develop a number of models for the joint distribution of image regions and words, including several which
            explicitly learn the correspondence between regions and words. We study multi-modal and correspondence
            extensions to Hofmann's hierarchical clustering/aspect model, a translation model adapted from statistical
            machine translation (Brown et at.), and a multi-modal extension to mixture of latent Dirichlet allocation
            (MoM-LDA). All models are assessed using a large collection of annotated images of real scenes. We study in
            depth the difficult problem of measuring performance. For the annotation task, we look at prediction
            performance on held out data. We present three alternative measures, oriented toward different types of
            task. Measuring the performance of correspondence methods is harder, because one must determine whether a
            word has been placed on the right region of an image. We can use annotation performance as a proxy measure,
            but accurate measurement requires hand labeled data, and thus must occur on a smaller scale. We show results
            using both an annotation proxy, and manually labeled data.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Selenay Aytac</authors>
        <title>Multilingual information retrieval on the Internet: A case study of Turkish users</title>
        <year>2005</year>
        <journal>INTERNATIONAL INFORMATION &amp; LIBRARY REVIEW</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Anwar, W., Wang, X., Li, L., Wang, X. L.</authors>
        <title>A statistical based part of speech tagger for Urdu language</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>3418-3424 4236</page>
        <journal>Proceedings of 2007 International Conference on Machine Learning and Cybernetics, Vols 1-7</journal>
        <abstract>In this paper we present a pioneering step in designing n-gram based part of speech tagger for the
            Urdu language. In the last few years part of speech tagging work has been done in the area of supposed
            English, South Asian and European languages. In this paper our focus of attention is on the disambiguation
            problem (to assign the accurate tag for every word of a set of possible tags). Our approach employs n-gram
            Markov Model, train from annotated Urdu corpus and assigns possible tags to text. The proposed n-gram part
            of speech tagger has been tested which achieved state of the art performance of 95.0%. Furthermore, we check
            our experiment results of two type of tagset. Along the way, we apply evaluation method that shows how
            significant our experiment results are. Besides, we present the error analysis (Confusion Matrix) and show
            the tagging example of Urdu tagging. We also present overview of Urdu language. The contribution of our work
            is an initial step of statistical based Urdu part of speech tagger.
        </abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Guychmyrat Amanmyradov</authors>
        <title>Karadeniz Teknik Universitesi FBE Bilgisayar Mu h endisligi anabilim dali Yuksek Lisans Tezi, Haziran
            2006.
        </title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <journal>Karadeniz Teknik Universitesi FBE Bilgisayar Mu h endisligi anabilim dali</journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Kemal Altintas, Fazli Can</authors>
        <title>Stemming for Turkish: A comparative evaluation</title>
        <year>2002</year>
        <journal>In Proceedings of the 11th Turkish Symposium on Artificial Intelligence and Neural Networks (TAINN
            2002)
        </journal>
        <page>Unknown</page>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Altingovde, I. S., Demir, E., Can, F., Ulusoy, O.</authors>
        <title>Incremental cluster-based retrieval using compressed cluster-skipping inverted files</title>
        <year>2008</year>
        <page>-</page>
        <journal>ACM Transactions on Information Systems</journal>
        <number>3</number>
        <volume>26</volume>
        <abstract>We propose a unique cluster-based retrieval (CBR) strategy using a new cluster-skipping inverted file
            for improving query processing efficiency. The new inverted file incorporates cluster membership and
            centroid information along with the usual document information into a single structure. In our
            incremental-CBR strategy, during query evaluation, both best(-matching) clusters and the best(-matching)
            documents of such clusters are computed together with a single posting-list access per query term. As we
            switch from term to term, the best clusters are recomputed and can dynamically change. During query-document
            matching, only relevant portions of the posting lists corresponding to the best clusters are considered and
            the rest are skipped. The proposed approach is essentially tailored for environments where inverted files
            are compressed, and provides substantial efficiency improvement while yielding comparable, or sometimes
            better, effectiveness figures. Our experiments with various collections show that the incremental- CBR
            strategy using a compressed cluster-skipping inverted file significantly improves CPU time efficiency,
            regardless of query length. The new compressed inverted file imposes an acceptable storage overhead in
            comparison to a typical inverted file. We also show that our approach scales well with the collection size.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Ismail Sengor Altingovde, Fazli Can, Ozgur Ulusoy</authors>
        <title>Algorithms for within cluster searches using inverted files</title>
        <year>2006</year>
        <page>707-716</page>
        <journal>In ISCIS'06</journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>H L Ak?n S Kuru, Tunga Gungor, I Hamzaoglu, D Arbatl?</authors>
        <title>A Spelling Checker and Corrector for Turkish</title>
        <year>1993</year>
        <page>113 - 120</page>
        <journal>International Second Turkish Symposium on Artificial Intelligence and Artificial Neural Networks (TAINN
            1993), Istanbul
        </journal>
        <abstract>Unknown</abstract>
        <volume>Unknown</volume>
        <number>Unknown</number>
    </handiwork>
    <handiwork>
        <authors>Adamek, T., O&amp;apos,Connor, N. E., Smeaton, A. F.</authors>
        <title>Word matching using single closed contours for indexing handwritten historical documents</title>
        <year>2007</year>
        <page>153-165</page>
        <journal>International Journal on Document Analysis and Recognition</journal>
        <number>2-4</number>
        <volume>9</volume>
        <abstract>Effective indexing is crucial for providing convenient access to scanned versions of large collections
            of historically valuable handwritten manuscripts. Since traditional handwriting recognizers based on optical
            character recognition (OCR) do not perform well on historical documents, recently a holistic word
            recognition approach has gained in popularity as an attractive and more straightforward solution (Lavrenko
            et al. in proc. document Image Analysis for Libraries (DIAL'04), pp. 278-287,2004). Such techniques attempt
            to recognize words based on scalar and profile-based features extracted from whole word images. In this
            paper, we propose a new approach to holistic word recognition for historical handwritten manuscripts based
            on matching word contours instead of whole images or word profiles. The new method consists of robust
            extraction of closed word contours and the application of an elastic contour matching technique proposed
            originally for general shapes (Adamek and O'Connor in IEEE Trans Circuits Syst Video Technol 5: 2004). We
            demonstrate that multiscale contour-based descriptors can effectively capture intrinsic word features
            avoiding any segmentation of words into smaller subunits. Our experiments show a recognition accuracy of
            83%, which considerably exceeds the performance of other systems reported in the literature.
        </abstract>
    </handiwork>
</handiworks>